<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!DOCTYPE COMMENTARYDOC PUBLIC "-//LEXISNEXIS//DTD GLP Commentarydoc v005//EN" "commentarydoc-norm.dtd">
<COMMENTARYDOC xmlns:case="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/case" xmlns:ci="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/ci" xmlns:comm="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/comm" xmlns:cttr="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/cttr" xmlns:dict="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/dict" xmlns:dig="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/dig" xmlns:docinfo="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/docinfo" xmlns:frm="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/frm" xmlns:glp="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp" xmlns:in="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/in" xmlns:jrnl="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/jrnl" xmlns:leg="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/leg" xmlns:lnci="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnci" xmlns:lncle="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lncle" xmlns:lnclx="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnclx" xmlns:lndel="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lndel" xmlns:lndocmeta="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lndocmeta" xmlns:lngntxt="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lngntxt" xmlns:lnlit="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnlit" xmlns:lnv="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnv" xmlns:lnvni="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnvni" xmlns:lnvx="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnvx" xmlns:lnvxe="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnvxe" xmlns:nitf="urn:nitf:iptc.org.20010418.NITF" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3c.org/1999/xhtml">
<docinfo partitionnum="1"><docinfo:dpsi id-string="05CC"/><docinfo:doc-heading>Precedents</docinfo:doc-heading><docinfo:doc-id>UCPN_LCPG.SGM_UCPN.LCPG.PRECEDENTS</docinfo:doc-id><docinfo:doc-lang lang="en"/><docinfo:doc-country iso-cc="AU"/><docinfo:hier><docinfo:hierlev role="ancestor"><heading><title>Local Court Practice Guide</title></heading><docinfo:hierlev role="ancestor"><heading><title>Precedents</title></heading><docinfo:hierlev role="me"><heading><title>Precedents</title></heading></docinfo:hierlev></docinfo:hierlev></docinfo:hierlev></docinfo:hier><docinfo:bookseqnum>100090000</docinfo:bookseqnum><docinfo:lbu-meta><docinfo:metaitem name="lbu-sourcename" value="Ritchie's Uniform Civil Procedure NSW"/><docinfo:metaitem name="parent-docid" value="UCPN.LCPG"/><docinfo:metaitem name="parent-filename" value="lcpg.xml"/><docinfo:metaitem name="parent-docid" value="UCPN_LCPG.SGM_UCPN.LCPG.PRECEDENTS"/><docinfo:metaitem name="parent-filename" value="lcpg1018.xml"/></docinfo:lbu-meta><docinfo:selector>commentary</docinfo:selector><docinfo:load-date><date day="10" month="11" year="2011">10 November 2011</date></docinfo:load-date></docinfo>
<comm:body>
<level id="UCPN_LCPG.SGM_UCPN.LCPG.PRECEDENTS" leveltype="comm.chap" subdoc="false">
<heading searchtype="COMMENTARY"><title><refpt id="UCPN.LCPG.PRECEDENTS" type="ext"/>Precedents</title></heading>
<level id="UCPN_LCPG.SGM_UCPN.LCPG.30000" leveltype="para0" subdoc="true" toc-caption="[30,000] 1. Claim for motor vehicle property damage deemed liquidated under UCPR r 14.13(2) &#x2014; plaintiff required to take evasive action to avoid a head-on collision &#x2014; formal parts omitted"><heading searchtype="COMMENTARY"><edpnum><refpt id="UCPN.LCPG.30000" type="ext"/>[30,000] </edpnum><title>1. Claim for motor vehicle property damage deemed liquidated under UCPR r 14.13(2) &#x2014; plaintiff required to take evasive action to avoid a head-on collision &#x2014; formal parts omitted</title></heading>
<bodytext searchtype="COMMENTARY">
<p>
<l>
<li>
<lilabel>1.</lilabel>
<p><text>On 25 January 2011, the plaintiff was driving his motor vehicle, a Mitsubishi station wagon, west along the Johnson Highway, Smithfield on the correct side of the carriageway.</text></p></li>
<li>
<lilabel>2.</lilabel>
<p><text>On the same day and at the same time, the defendants were driving their respective motor vehicles in the opposite direction along the same highway.</text></p></li>
<li>
<lilabel>3.</lilabel>
<p><text>The first defendant so negligently, carelessly and unskilfully drove his motor vehicle that it came to a standstill on a steep hill, thereby causing a nuisance and a hazard to other road users, in particular the plaintiff and the second defendant.</text></p></li>
<li>
<lilabel>4.</lilabel>
<p><text>The first defendant thereafter so negligently, carelessly and unskilfully conducted himself that he signalled the second defendant to drive around his stationary vehicle into the path of the plaintiff's vehicle when it was unsafe to do so, thereby causing the plaintiff to take evasive action to avoid a collision, in turn resulting in the plaintiff's vehicle colliding with an adjacent guard rail and other vehicles in the vicinity causing it to sustain extensive damage.</text></p></li>
<li>
<lilabel>5.</lilabel>
<p><text>The second defendant so negligently, carelessly and unskilfully drove, managed and controlled her vehicle that she relied upon the first defendant's signal to drive around her vehicle and drove into the path of the plaintiff&#x2019;s vehicle, thereby causing the plaintiff to take evasive action to avoid a collision, in turn resulting in the plaintiff's vehicle colliding with an adjacent guard rail and other vehicles in the vicinity causing it to sustain extensive damage.</text></p></li></l></p>
<pgrp>
<heading><title>Particulars of the first defendant's negligence</title></heading>
<p>
<l>
<li>
<lilabel>i.</lilabel>
<p><text>Driving a motor vehicle on a public road in such a condition that it was unable to maintain traction on the roadway in all prevailing weather and road conditions.</text></p></li>
<li>
<lilabel>ii.</lilabel>
<p><text>Attempting to drive up a steep incline in wet conditions in a vehicle ill suited for that purpose.</text></p></li>
<li>
<lilabel>iii.</lilabel>
<p><text>Failing to maintain the vehicle and in particular its tyres so as to enable it to maintain traction on the roadway in all prevailing weather and road conditions.</text></p></li>
<li>
<lilabel>iv.</lilabel>
<p><text>Causing or suffering the vehicle to lose traction on the roadway whilst in the process of driving up an incline in wet conditions, or attempting to do so.</text></p></li>
<li>
<lilabel>v.</lilabel>
<p><text>Causing or suffering the vehicle to lose forward momentum on the roadway whilst in the process of driving up an incline in wet conditions, or attempting to do so.</text></p></li>
<li>
<lilabel>vi.</lilabel>
<p><text>Signalling the second defendant to drive around the first defendant's vehicle into the path of the plaintiff&#x2019;s vehicle when it was unsafe to do so.</text></p></li>
<li>
<lilabel>vii.</lilabel>
<p><text>Failing to take account of the prevailing weather conditions when signalling the second defendant to drive around the first defendant's vehicle.</text></p></li>
<li>
<lilabel>viii.</lilabel>
<p><text>Failing to keep a proper lookout.</text></p></li>
<li>
<lilabel>ix.</lilabel>
<p><text>Failing to take due care in all the circumstances.</text></p></li></l></p></pgrp>
<pgrp>
<heading><title>Particulars of the second defendant's negligence</title></heading>
<p>
<l>
<li>
<lilabel>i.</lilabel>
<p><text>Failing to keep a proper lookout.</text></p></li>
<li>
<lilabel>ii.</lilabel>
<p><text>Driving on the wrong side of the road.</text></p></li>
<li>
<lilabel>iii.</lilabel>
<p><text>Failing to exercise reasonable care in accepting directions from the first defendant to drive around his vehicle when it was unsafe to do so.</text></p></li>
<li>
<lilabel>iv.</lilabel>
<p><text>Failing to make an appropriate judgment whether it was safe to proceed around the first defendant's stalled vehicle onto the wrong side of the road. </text></p></li>
<li>
<lilabel>v.</lilabel>
<p><text>Failing to exercise due care in driving around the stalled vehicle when it was unsafe to do so.</text></p></li>
<li>
<lilabel>vi.</lilabel>
<p><text>Failing to see the plaintiff's vehicle until it was too late to avoid the driver of the plaintiff&#x2019;s vehicle being forced off the carriageway.</text></p></li>
<li>
<lilabel>vii.</lilabel>
<p><text>Failing to drive in accordance with the prevailing weather conditions.</text></p></li>
<li>
<lilabel>viii.</lilabel>
<p><text>Failing to drive in such a manner as to enable her vehicle to be efficiently and safely brought to a halt in an emergency.</text></p></li>
<li>
<lilabel>ix.</lilabel>
<p><text>Failing to drive at an appropriate speed so as to enable her vehicle to be brought to a halt in an emergency.</text></p></li>
<li>
<lilabel>x.</lilabel>
<p><text>Failing to exercise due care in all the circumstances.</text></p></li></l></p></pgrp>
<pgrp>
<heading><title>Particulars of damage</title></heading>
<p>
<l>
<li>
<lilabel>6.</lilabel>
<p><text>The plaintiff's vehicle sustained extensive damage as follows:</text></p></li></l>
<table frame="none" pgwide="1">
<tgroup align="left" cols="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<colspec colname="col1" colsep="0" colwidth="75*" rowsep="0"/>
<colspec colname="col2" colsep="0" colwidth="225*" rowsep="0"/>
<tbody valign="top"><row rowsep="0"><entry colsep="0" morerows="0" rowsep="0">Cost of repairs</entry>
<entry colsep="0" morerows="0" rowsep="0">$3,692.04</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
<l>
<li>
<lilabel> </lilabel>
<p><text>And the plaintiff claims the sum of $3,852.04, particulars whereof are as follows:</text></p></li></l>
<table frame="none" pgwide="1">
<tgroup align="left" cols="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<colspec colname="col1" colsep="0" colwidth="75*" rowsep="0"/>
<colspec colname="col2" colsep="0" colwidth="225*" rowsep="0"/>
<tbody valign="top"><row rowsep="0"><entry colsep="0" morerows="0" rowsep="0">Cost of repairs</entry>
<entry colsep="0" morerows="0" rowsep="0">$3,692.04</entry>
</row>
<row rowsep="0"><entry colsep="0" morerows="0" rowsep="0">Towing</entry>
<entry colsep="0" morerows="0" rowsep="0">$160.00</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</p>
<p>
<text><emph typestyle="bf">Editorial Note:</emph> the procedure for signing default judgment on a statement of claim under r 14.13(2) is set out in Pt 16 r 16.6.</text></p></pgrp>
</bodytext>
</level><level id="UCPN_LCPG.SGM_UCPN.LCPG.30010" leveltype="para0" subdoc="true" toc-caption="[30,010] 2. Affidavit responding to application for change of venue from one Local Court to another under Chief Magistrate&#x2019;s Practice Note Civ 1 of 2011 at [LC Civ 1 of 2011] and UCPR r 8.2 &#x2014; Local Court Small Claims Division &#x2014; omitting formal parts as to which see UCPR Form 40 (Affidavit)">
<glp:note><blockquote><hrule/>
<p>
<text><inlineobject attachment="web-server" filename="leg1.gif" type="image"/> Legislation cited in [30,010] below. LawNow subscribers click through for daily updates and historical versions.</text><text> </text>
<text>(NSW) <ci:cite searchtype="LEG-REF"><ci:content><remotelink alttext="Click to link to LawNow Legislation" dpsi="005Y" refpt="NSW_ACT_2007-93" remotekey1="REFPTID" service="DOC-ID">Local Court Act 2007</remotelink> s 55.</ci:content></ci:cite></text>
</p></blockquote></glp:note><heading searchtype="COMMENTARY"><edpnum><refpt id="UCPN.LCPG.30010" type="ext"/>[30,010] </edpnum><title>2. Affidavit responding to application for change of venue from one Local Court to another under Chief Magistrate&#x2019;s Practice Note Civ 1 of 2011 at [LC Civ 1 of 2011] and UCPR r 8.2 &#x2014; Local Court Small Claims Division &#x2014; omitting formal parts as to which see UCPR Form 40 (Affidavit)</title></heading>
<bodytext searchtype="COMMENTARY">
<p>
<l>
<li>
<lilabel>1.</lilabel>
<p><text>I am the plaintiff.</text></p></li></l></p>
<pgrp>
<heading><title>Submissions on law</title></heading>
<p>
<l>
<li>
<lilabel>2.</lilabel>
<p><text>Change of venue is governed by the Local Court Act 2007 
<ci:cite searchtype="LEG-REF"><ci:content><remotelink dpsi="05CC" refpt="UCPN.LC.LCAN07.S55" remotekey1="REFPTID" service="DOC-ID">s 55</remotelink></ci:content></ci:cite>
 which states that the court may make an order changing the proceedings &#x201c;if it thinks it appropriate in the circumstances&#x201d;.</text></p></li>
<li>
<lilabel>3.</lilabel>
<p><text>Chief Magistrates Practice Note Civ 1 of 2011, cl 11 states that the plaintiff's affidavit is to address &#x201c;the matters contained in UCPR 8.2.and (identify) the reasons upon which the applicant relies for the change of the venue&#x201d;.</text></p></li>
<li>
<lilabel>4.</lilabel>
<p><text>I submit the plaintiff has not appropriately done so.</text></p></li>
<li>
<lilabel>5.</lilabel>
<p><text>The affidavit of Bill Smith Solicitor dated 2 February 2011 refers only to balance of convenience factors which are no longer relevant under the statutory provisions referred to in cll 2 and 3 above.</text></p></li>
<li>
<lilabel>6.</lilabel>
<p><text>Under UCPR r 8.2(1)(a), the test for a change of venue is &#x201c;that a fair or unprejudiced trial of a question arising or likely to arise in the proceedings cannot otherwise be had&#x201d;, but under subr (1)(b), a change may be made &#x201c;for any other reason&#x201d;.</text></p></li>
<li>
<lilabel>7.</lilabel>
<p><text>Subrule (1)(b) should be read <emph typestyle="it">eiusdem generis</emph> with subr (1)(a), in the context of whether a fair or unprejudiced trial cannot be otherwise be held. The balance of convenience factors specified in Local Court (Civil Claims) Rules 1988 Pt 3 r 4, which required the plaintiff to list all the &#x201c;appropriate courts&#x201d; and make a make a selection now no longer apply.</text></p></li>
<li>
<lilabel>8.</lilabel>
<p><text>Furthermore, since the commencement of the Local Courts Act 2005, the Local Court is now a single entity and not a collection of disparate courts as it was under the Local Courts (Civil Claims) Act 1970.</text></p></li>
<li>
<lilabel>9.</lilabel>
<p><text>The test in Chief Magistrates Practice Note cl 11.3, to the effect that &#x201c;a change of venue to another venue less than 100 kilometres from the original venue will not be granted unless exceptional circumstances are granted&#x201d; is a negative test, which an order for change of venue cannot be made unless exceptional circumstances are made. It does not mean or say that if the distance between those courts is more than 100 kms, then an order for a change of venue should or must be made.</text></p></li>
<li>
<lilabel>10.</lilabel>
<p><text>The test under UCPR r 8.2 remains whether &#x201c;a fair or unprejudiced trial of a question arising or likely to arise in the proceedings cannot otherwise be had&#x201d; or, within that context, whether a change should be made &#x201c;for any other reason&#x201d;.</text></p></li>
<li>
<lilabel>11.</lilabel>
<p><text>In my submission, that stringent test has not been met.</text></p></li></l></p></pgrp>
<pgrp>
<heading><title>Submissions on the facts</title></heading>
<p>
<l>
<li>
<lilabel>12.</lilabel>
<p><text>This is a matter being heard in the court's Small Claims Division, and in the normal course, no witnesses are required to be called. The matter is dealt with upon statements exchanged between the parties, and submissions by the parties. The convenience of witnesses is therefore not a factor. There is therefore no substantial reason why these proceedings should not remain in Grafton where they were commenced, rather than be transferred to Lismore.</text></p></li>
<li>
<lilabel>13.</lilabel>
<p><text>Further, the distance between Grafton and Lismore is approximately 135 kms &#x2014; little more than an hour's drive.</text></p></li>
<li>
<lilabel>14.</lilabel>
<p><text>(Insert any other relevant particulars).</text></p></li>
<li>
<lilabel>15.</lilabel>
<p><text>For the foregoing reasons, I seek that the venue of these proceedings remain at Grafton.</text></p></li></l></p></pgrp>
</bodytext>
</level></level>
</comm:body>
</COMMENTARYDOC>