<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!DOCTYPE COMMENTARYDOC PUBLIC "-//LEXISNEXIS//DTD GLP Commentarydoc v005//EN" "commentarydoc-norm.dtd">
<COMMENTARYDOC xmlns:case="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/case" xmlns:ci="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/ci" xmlns:comm="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/comm" xmlns:cttr="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/cttr" xmlns:dict="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/dict" xmlns:dig="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/dig" xmlns:docinfo="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/docinfo" xmlns:frm="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/frm" xmlns:glp="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp" xmlns:in="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/in" xmlns:jrnl="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/jrnl" xmlns:leg="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/leg" xmlns:lnci="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnci" xmlns:lncle="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lncle" xmlns:lnclx="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnclx" xmlns:lndel="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lndel" xmlns:lndocmeta="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lndocmeta" xmlns:lngntxt="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lngntxt" xmlns:lnlit="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnlit" xmlns:lnv="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnv" xmlns:lnvni="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnvni" xmlns:lnvx="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnvx" xmlns:lnvxe="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnvxe" xmlns:nitf="urn:nitf:iptc.org.20010418.NITF" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3c.org/1999/xhtml">
<docinfo partitionnum="1"><docinfo:dpsi id-string="05CC"/><docinfo:doc-heading>Introduction: Local Court Practice Guide</docinfo:doc-heading><docinfo:doc-id>UCPN_LCPG.SGM_COMM.INTRO_2</docinfo:doc-id><docinfo:doc-lang lang="en"/><docinfo:doc-country iso-cc="AU"/><docinfo:hier><docinfo:hierlev role="ancestor"><heading><title>Local Court Practice Guide</title></heading><docinfo:hierlev role="ancestor"><heading><title>Introduction: Local Court Practice Guide</title></heading><docinfo:hierlev role="me"><heading><title>Introduction: Local Court Practice Guide</title></heading></docinfo:hierlev></docinfo:hierlev></docinfo:hierlev></docinfo:hier><docinfo:bookseqnum>100000000</docinfo:bookseqnum><docinfo:lbu-meta><docinfo:metaitem name="lbu-sourcename" value="Ritchie's Uniform Civil Procedure NSW"/><docinfo:metaitem name="parent-docid" value="UCPN.LCPG"/><docinfo:metaitem name="parent-filename" value="lcpg.xml"/><docinfo:metaitem name="parent-docid" value="UCPN_LCPG.SGM_PARA0_1"/><docinfo:metaitem name="parent-filename" value="lcpg1000.xml"/></docinfo:lbu-meta><docinfo:selector>commentary</docinfo:selector><docinfo:load-date><date day="10" month="11" year="2011">10 November 2011</date></docinfo:load-date></docinfo>
<comm:body>
<level id="UCPN_LCPG.SGM_COMM.INTRO_2" leveltype="comm.intro" subdoc="false">
<heading searchtype="COMMENTARY"><title>Introduction: Local Court Practice Guide</title></heading>
<level id="UCPN_LCPG.SGM_UCPN.LCPG.20000" leveltype="para0" subdoc="true" toc-caption="[20,000]">
<glp:note><blockquote><hrule/>
<p>
<text><inlineobject attachment="web-server" filename="leg1.gif" type="image"/> Legislation cited in [20,000] below. LawNow subscribers click through for daily updates and historical versions.</text><text> </text>
<text>(NSW) <ci:cite searchtype="LEG-REF"><ci:content><remotelink alttext="Click to link to LawNow Legislation" dpsi="005Y" refpt="NSW_REG_1988-4" remotekey1="REFPTID" service="DOC-ID">Local Courts (Civil Claims) Rules 1988</remotelink>.</ci:content></ci:cite></text>
<text>(NSW) <ci:cite searchtype="LEG-REF"><ci:content><remotelink alttext="Click to link to LawNow Legislation" dpsi="005Y" refpt="NSW_ACT_1970-11" remotekey1="REFPTID" service="DOC-ID">Local Courts (Civil Claims) Act 1970</remotelink>.</ci:content></ci:cite></text>
<text>(NSW) <ci:cite searchtype="LEG-REF"><ci:content><remotelink alttext="Click to link to LawNow Legislation" dpsi="005Y" refpt="NSW_ACT_1983-43" remotekey1="REFPTID" service="DOC-ID">Arbitration (Civil Actions) Act 1983</remotelink>.</ci:content></ci:cite></text>
<text>(NSW) <ci:cite searchtype="LEG-REF"><ci:content><remotelink alttext="Click to link to LawNow Legislation" dpsi="005Y" refpt="NSW_ACT_1989-169" remotekey1="REFPTID" service="DOC-ID" status="unval">Courts Legislation (Procedure) Amendment Act 1989</remotelink> s 3, Sch 6.</ci:content></ci:cite></text>
</p></blockquote></glp:note><heading searchtype="COMMENTARY"><edpnum><refpt id="UCPN.LCPG.20000" type="ext"/>[20,000] </edpnum></heading>
<bodytext searchtype="COMMENTARY">
<p>
<text>Although some 35 years have now passed, to many of us it seems but a short time since the 
<ci:cite searchtype="LEG-REF"><ci:content><remotelink dpsi="05CC" refpt="OTH.SDR61" remotekey1="REFPTID" service="DOC-ID" status="unval">Small Debts Recovery Act</remotelink></ci:content></ci:cite>
 governed civil claims towards the lower end of the jurisdictional scale in this State. Indeed, such was the impact of this Act, which was the source of jurisdiction of Courts of Petty Sessions in minor claims for almost 70 years, that until the last decade or so, the uninformed still tended to refer to the jurisdiction of Local Courts in these kinds of matters as &#x201c;Small Debts&#x201d;. To those who practice regularly in this jurisdiction, it is evident that while the sums involved are smaller than those which are the subject of litigation in the Supreme and District Courts, the amounts involved often bear little or no relation to the complexities of the issues involved. The jurisdiction is well known for its tendency to spawn just about every aspect of tort and contract law and many more besides. Nor, one might add, are the sums involved necessarily considered small by the litigants involved. Changes in the value of money over recent years, and the impact of court arrears building up in the superior jurisdictions have also meant that the Local Courts are now dealing with far greater sums than was the case a few years ago, a trend which culminated in the passing of the 
<ci:cite searchtype="LEG-REF"><ci:content>Courts Legislation (Civil Procedure) Amendment Act, No 12 of 1991</ci:content></ci:cite>
 (assented to 3 May of that year) whereby the Local Courts jurisdiction in civil matters was raised to $40,000, some 4 times the extent of its pecuniary jurisdiction, prior to the passing of the Act. As a result of successive increases in the court's jurisdiction, it became necessary to streamline the court's procedures, and on 1 July 1989 the Local Court was endowed with rules which essentially mirrored the rules operative in the District and Supreme Courts, although there were significant differences. In more recent times, the jurisdiction of the Local Court&#x2019;s General Division has been raised to $60,000 (subsequently $100,000 by the Courts and Crimes Legislation Further Amendment Act, No 135 of 2010, Sch 15[2], commenced 7 December 2010) and with the passing of the Civil Procedure Act and the Uniform Civil Procedure Rules, the Local Court now has procedures and rules which place it on essentially the same plane as its judicial counterparts further up the hierarchy, the District and Supreme Courts. These recent developments are the culmination of a legislative tendency which dates back to the early days of the colony.</text></p>
<p>
<text>During the 1790s magistrates dealt informally with disputes involving small sums of money although their constitutional base for so doing was at best doubtful. This informal jurisdiction was withdrawn in 1799, reinstated by Governor Macquarie in 1810 (in respect of matters where the amount in dispute was less than forty shillings), and then withdrawn again by the Charter of Justice 1814, which conferred an exclusive jurisdiction in respect of suits involving less than £50 upon the newly formed Governor's  Court.</text></p>
<p>
<text>It was the Statute 
<ci:cite searchtype="LEG-REF"><ci:content><remotelink dpsi="05CC" refpt="Q.Q.Q" remotekey1="REFPTID" service="DOC-ID" status="unval">9 Geo IV c 83</remotelink></ci:content></ci:cite>
 by which English law was received into New South Wales. 
<ci:cite searchtype="LEG-REF"><ci:content><remotelink dpsi="05CC" refpt="Q.Q.Q.S24" remotekey1="REFPTID" service="DOC-ID" status="unval">Section 24</remotelink></ci:content></ci:cite>
 provided that all laws and statutes in force  within the realm of England on 25 July 1828, should be applied in the administration of justice in the courts of New South Wales and Van Dieman's Land &#x201c;so far as the same could be applied within those colonies&#x201d;. Soon after 
<ci:cite searchtype="LEG-REF"><ci:content><remotelink dpsi="05CC" refpt="Q.Q.Q" remotekey1="REFPTID" service="DOC-ID" status="unval">9 Geo IV c 83</remotelink></ci:content></ci:cite>
 was passed by the Imperial Parliament and pursuant to the power conferred therein, an Act or Ordinance of the Governor-in-Council 
<ci:cite searchtype="LEG-REF"><ci:content><remotelink dpsi="05CC" refpt="Q.Q.Q" remotekey1="REFPTID" service="DOC-ID" status="unval">10 Geo IV No 3</remotelink></ci:content></ci:cite>
 established Courts of Requests in  New South Wales. These courts had been created in England from the reign of James I onwards as local Small Debts Courts to process the enforcement of small claims. By 
<ci:cite searchtype="LEG-REF"><ci:content><remotelink dpsi="05CC" refpt="Q.Q.Q" remotekey1="REFPTID" service="DOC-ID" status="unval">10 Geo IV No 3</remotelink></ci:content></ci:cite>
 Courts of Requests were established  in the districts of Sydney, Windsor, Campbelltown, Parramatta, Maitland and Bathurst and were given &#x201c;Full power and authority to hear and determine in a summary way all actions, plaints or suits for the payment and recovery of any debt, damages or matter  not exceeding ten pounds sterling except the matter in question should relate to any title of any lands tenements or hereditaments or to the taking of any duty payable to His Majesty or to any fee of office, annual rent or other such matter where rights in future  might be bound or any general right or duty and to award costs therein.&#x201d; As a safeguard against the unjustified commencement of actions for less than £10 in the Supreme Court, the Act provided that in that circumstance, if the plaintiff were successful,  he should not have costs, but that if the defendant were successful, he should have double costs!</text></p>
<p>
<text>On 15 August 1832, the 1829 Act was repealed and the Statute 
<ci:cite searchtype="LEG-REF"><ci:content><remotelink dpsi="05CC" refpt="Q.Q.Q" remotekey1="REFPTID" service="DOC-ID" status="unval">3 Wm IV c 2</remotelink></ci:content></ci:cite>
 established Courts of Requests in the County of Cumberland at the towns of Sydney, Parramatta, Liverpool, Penrith, Windsor and  Campbelltown; in the County of Camden at the towns of Wollongong and Bong Bong or Berrima; in the County of Bathurst at the town of Bathurst; and in the County of Northumberland at the town of Maitland. The courts' jurisdictional limit remained at £10  sterling. The Act contained a sanction against the splitting or dividing of causes of action, and a provision that suits in Courts of Requests were to be brought in the court nearest to the defendant's residence and no defendant was to be summoned more than  30 miles &#x2014; the genesis of the provisions governing venue which have since become a hallmark of small debts and civil claims legislation. In 1839 Courts of Requests were established at the towns of Melbourne and Port Macquarie in the colony of New South  Wales, and in the following year the Governor was given a discretion to appoint further venues where Courts of Requests might be held.</text></p>
<p>
<text>On 30 October 1846 the 
<ci:cite searchtype="LEG-REF"><ci:content><remotelink dpsi="05CC" refpt="Q.Q.Q" remotekey1="REFPTID" service="DOC-ID" status="unval">Small Debts Recovery Act</remotelink></ci:content></ci:cite>
 of that year established Courts of Petty Sessions as Courts of Requests. Courts of Petty Sessions had hitherto exercised a summary jurisdiction under  the Statute 
<ci:cite searchtype="LEG-REF"><ci:content><remotelink dpsi="05CC" refpt="Q.Q.Q" remotekey1="REFPTID" service="DOC-ID" status="unval">3 Wm IV No 3</remotelink></ci:content></ci:cite>
 to &#x201c;take cognisance of&#x201d; misdemeanours and simple larcenies to the value of £5 and under. They were now endowed with &#x201c;power and authority to hear and determine  in a summary way and according to equity and good conscience all actions whatsoever &#x2026; for the recovery of any debt, demand or damage whether liquidated or unliquidated to an amount in any case not exceeding ten pounds or (where the party intended to be  sued shall by writing under his hand have consented thereto) to an amount not exceeding thirty pounds&#x201d;. There were again a number of exceptions to jurisdiction, for example, where the matter in question related to the taking of any duty to the Crown or  where the debt sought to be recovered was the result of a gaming or wagering contract. If the cause of action was trespass and the title to the freehold of the land in question was bona fide in dispute between the parties the Court of Petty Sessions was without  the power to adjudicate thereon. At the same time the jurisdiction of Courts of Requests other than Courts of Petty Sessions was raised to £30, and &#x201c;all actions tried in any such Court of Requests for the recovery of any sum between ten pounds and  thirty pounds shall be heard and determined in a summary way and according to equity and good conscience in like manner as any sum under ten pounds is now recoverable in any such court&#x201d;. A Court of Requests was also established in the County of Bourke. </text></p>
<p>
<text>The Act of 1846 contained numerous procedural provisions governing the situation where a party did not appear, the commencement of suits in Courts of Petty Sessions, how summonses were to be served and an affidavit of service made. It is interesting to note that such or similar provisions have remained in the successive statutes governing small claims recovery in this state right down to the advent of the 
<ci:cite searchtype="LEG-REF"><ci:content><remotelink dpsi="05CC" refpt="OTH.CPSCN70" remotekey1="REFPTID" service="DOC-ID" status="unval">Court of Petty Sessions (Civil  Claims) Act of 1970</remotelink></ci:content></ci:cite>
 . Since the commencement of the 
<ci:cite searchtype="LEG-REF"><ci:content><remotelink dpsi="05CC" refpt="LCCN.LCR.LCCR" remotekey1="REFPTID" service="DOC-ID" status="unval">Local Courts (Civil Claims) Rules</remotelink></ci:content></ci:cite>
 on 1 July 1989 such matters are governed by the Rules. For the first time,  the Act of 1846 constituted Courts of Petty Sessions as Courts of Record for the purposes of small debts recovery. The Act contained the well-known sanction against the splitting and dividing of causes of actions, and a venue provision that actions were to be  brought in a Court of Petty Sessions for the district where the defendant resided. The 45th section of the Act provided &#x201c;that it shall be lawful for any Court of Petty Sessions if it shall appear to such Court that any attorney or other agent has in any  cause in such Court practised corruptly contemptuously or in any respect knowingly and wilfully against his duty as an attorney or agent, to make an order (to remain with the Registrar of the said Court) either to suspend such attorney or agent from practising  for a specified time or to prohibit such attorney or agent from practising for ever in such Court&#x201d;! No court fees were payable in actions for sums not exceeding £30.</text></p>
<p>
<text>In 1870 the 
<ci:cite searchtype="LEG-REF"><ci:content><remotelink dpsi="05CC" refpt="Q.Q.Q" remotekey1="REFPTID" service="DOC-ID" status="unval">Small Debts Act of 1846</remotelink></ci:content></ci:cite>
 was extended to all parts of the colony except the Police District of Sydney, which was finally included in 1879, and in 1880  the Executive was given the power to define Petty Sessions Districts for the purposes of the Small Debts Act. In 1881 45 Vic No 27 entitled &#x201c;An Act for the better recovery of Judgment Debts in District Courts and in Courts of Petty Sessions&#x201d; enacted  for the first time those now indispensable machinery provisions facilitating the enforcement of judgment debts: examination of judgment debtor, attachment and garnishee. In 1892 the jurisdiction of the Courts of Petty Sessions was raised to £30 and in  the following year the court was given the power to authorise the payment of the judgment debt by instalments.</text></p>
<p>
<text>In 1899 the 
<remotelink dpsi="05CC" refpt="Q.Q.Q" remotekey1="REFPTID" service="DOC-ID" status="unval">Small Debts Recovery Act</remotelink>
 consolidated the various Acts relating to small debts recovery in Courts of Petty Sessions in New South Wales into a single Act. The Act's structure reflected that dichotomy between parts  devoted to jurisdiction and parts devoted to procedure which has remained the hallmark of the legislation governing smaller civil claims recovery ever since, right down to the statute presently in force. The courts' power and authority was again &#x201c;to hear  and determine (disputes) in a summary way and according to equity and good conscience&#x201d;. Districts outside the Metropolitan Police District were endowed with jurisdiction up to £30, and within the Metropolitan Police District up to £10, with  consent jurisdiction up to £30. With some exceptions, all judgments and orders of the court were final and conclusive.</text></p>
<p>
<text>In 1905 (Act No 18), the extent of the courts' jurisdiction was raised to £50, whether on balance of account of after admitted set-off or otherwise. A provision was inserted into the Act authorising the court to set aside a judgment on sufficient  cause being shown &#x201c;where the judgment was entered up in the absence of the defendant, or for neglect to file notice of grounds of defence and any execution thereupon&#x201d;. The court was given the power to non suit, if the plaintiff did not appear, to  record a judgment following a confession or agreement, and to order a change of venue if the court was satisfied &#x201c;that any action or other proceeding therein pending can be more conveniently or fairly tried or determined by some other court&#x201d;, language  which is repeated verbatim in 
<ci:cite searchtype="LEG-REF"><ci:content><remotelink dpsi="05CC" refpt="Q.Q.Q.S18" remotekey1="REFPTID" service="DOC-ID" status="unval">s 18</remotelink></ci:content></ci:cite>
 of the Act presently in force. In order to execute upon a judgment obtained in a Court of Petty Sessions, it was necessary to obtain a certificate of unsatisfied judgment  and to file it in the District Court whereupon execution issued from that court.</text></p>
<p>
<text>In 1912, the 
<ci:cite searchtype="LEG-REF"><ci:content><remotelink dpsi="05CC" refpt="Q.Q.Q" remotekey1="REFPTID" service="DOC-ID" status="unval">Small Debts Recovery Act of 1899</remotelink></ci:content></ci:cite>
 was repealed and replaced by another Act bearing the same title. All courts were given power to hear and determine disputes in their respective districts  for amounts up to £30, but where the proceedings were heard by a Stipendiary or Police Magistrate the jurisdiction was £50. That sum remained intact for nearly 50 years until it was raised in 1961 to £150. Finally in 1970 the 
<ci:cite searchtype="LEG-REF"><ci:content><remotelink dpsi="05CC" refpt="OTH.CPSCN70" remotekey1="REFPTID" service="DOC-ID" status="unval">Courts of Petty Sessions (Civil Claims) Act</remotelink></ci:content></ci:cite>
 was passed which repealed the 
<ci:cite searchtype="LEG-REF"><ci:content><remotelink dpsi="05CC" refpt="OTH.SDRAN12" remotekey1="REFPTID" service="DOC-ID" status="unval">Small Debts Recovery Act of 1912</remotelink></ci:content></ci:cite>
 and conferred upon the court  jurisdiction to hear and determine actions for the recovery of any debt demand or damage whether liquidated or unliquidated, or the detention of goods, in which the amount claimed was not more than $500, whether on a balance of account or after an admitted set-off  or otherwise. That figure has since been raised to $2000 by Act No 106 of 1975; to $3000 by Act No 61 of 1980, which commenced 1 June 1981; to $5000 by Act No 42 of 1982, which commenced on 1 April 1983; and to $10,000 by Act No 281 of 1987, which commenced on  1 February 1988. This Act also conferred upon the court jurisdiction to hear and determine property damage claims arising from motor vehicle accidents where the amount claimed did not exceed $20,000. The 
<ci:cite searchtype="LEG-REF"><ci:content><remotelink dpsi="05CC" refpt="Q.Q.Q" remotekey1="REFPTID" service="DOC-ID" status="unval">Courts Legislation  (Civil Procedure) Amendment Act of 1991</remotelink></ci:content></ci:cite>
 (assented to on 3 May 1991) endowed the court with jurisdiction to hear and determine claims of up to $40,000, four times the limit of the court's previous power and some 40% of the jurisdiction hitherto enjoyed  by the District Court. Having remained static for almost 50 years, the uppermost limit of the court's jurisdiction had increased in leaps and bounds from
$300 to $40,000 in the last 30 years.</text></p>
<p>
<text>In the meantime, other changes were taking place which were to have a profound effect on the status of those courts exercising jurisdiction in civil claims litigation. One thing upon which the various statutes governing small debts and civil claims  recovery were (and in fact remain) silent was whether the court was required to keep a written record of the proceedings. For example, there is no specific provision in the 
<ci:cite searchtype="LEG-REF"><ci:content><remotelink dpsi="05CC" refpt="LCCN.LCA.LCCCN" remotekey1="REFPTID" service="DOC-ID" status="unval">Local Courts (Civil Claims) Act, 1970</remotelink></ci:content></ci:cite>
 which requires depositions or other record of the testimony of witnesses to be taken, and for many years under both the 
<ci:cite searchtype="LEG-REF"><ci:content><remotelink dpsi="05CC" refpt="OTH.SDRAN12" remotekey1="REFPTID" service="DOC-ID" status="unval">Small Debts Recovery Act  of 1912</remotelink></ci:content></ci:cite>
 and the 
<ci:cite searchtype="LEG-REF"><ci:content><remotelink dpsi="05CC" refpt="OTH.CPSCN70" remotekey1="REFPTID" service="DOC-ID" status="unval">Courts of Petty Sessions (Civil Claims) Act of 1970</remotelink></ci:content></ci:cite>
 , it was not the practice for depositions to be taken when such matters were heard.
This practice was finally  laid to rest by the Supreme Court in <ci:cite searchtype="CASE-REF"><ci:case><ci:caseref ID="cr000001" spanref="cr000001-001"><ci:reporter value="NSWLR"/><ci:volume num="1"/><ci:edition><ci:date year="1979"/></ci:edition><ci:page num="279"/></ci:caseref></ci:case><ci:content><citefragment searchtype="CASE-NAME-REF"><emph typestyle="it">Pinkstone v Goldrick</emph></citefragment><citefragment searchtype="CASE-CITE-REF"> <ci:span spanid="cr000001-001">[1979] 1 NSWLR 279</ci:span></citefragment></ci:content></ci:cite> , where it was held that a magistrate,  sitting as a court under 
<ci:cite searchtype="LEG-REF"><ci:content><remotelink dpsi="05CC" refpt="OTH.CPSCN70.S12.1" remotekey1="REFPTID" service="DOC-ID" status="unval">s 12(1)</remotelink></ci:content></ci:cite>
 of the Act presently in force, is required to keep a proper record of the proceedings, including the evidence, and that failure to do so will invalidate  the proceedings, since it effectively deprives a party of his right of appeal under 
<ci:cite searchtype="LEG-REF"><ci:content><remotelink dpsi="05CC" refpt="OTH.CPSCN70.S69.2" remotekey1="REFPTID" service="DOC-ID" status="unval">s 69(2)</remotelink></ci:content></ci:cite>
 and 
<ci:cite searchtype="LEG-REF"><ci:content><remotelink dpsi="05CC" refpt="OTH.CPSCN70.S69.3" remotekey1="REFPTID" service="DOC-ID" status="unval">(3)</remotelink></ci:content></ci:cite>
 .  See also <ci:cite searchtype="CASE-REF"><ci:case><ci:caseinfo><ci:decisiondate year="1943"/></ci:caseinfo><ci:caseref ID="cr000002" spanref="cr000002-001" status="unval"><ci:reporter value="SRNSW"/><ci:volume num="43"/><ci:page num="207"/></ci:caseref><ci:caseref anaphref="cr000002" spanref="cr000002-002"><ci:pinpoint num="212" targettype="page"/></ci:caseref><ci:caseref anaphref="cr000002" spanref="cr000002-003" status="unval"><ci:pinpoint num="213" targettype="page"/></ci:caseref><ci:caseref ID="cr000003" spanref="cr000003-004" status="unval"><ci:reporter value="WN"/><ci:volume num="60"/><ci:page num="148"/></ci:caseref><ci:caseref anaphref="cr000003" spanref="cr000003-005" status="unval"><ci:pinpoint num="151" targettype="page"/></ci:caseref></ci:case><ci:content><citefragment searchtype="CASE-NAME-REF"><emph typestyle="it">Ex parte Reid; Re Lynch</emph></citefragment><citefragment searchtype="CASE-CITE-REF"> <ci:span spanid="cr000002-001" status="unval">(1943) 43 SR (NSW) 207</ci:span> <ci:span spanid="cr000002-002">at 212,</ci:span> <ci:span spanid="cr000002-003" status="unval">213</ci:span>; <ci:span spanid="cr000003-004" status="unval">60 WN (NSW) 148</ci:span> <ci:span spanid="cr000003-005" status="unval">at 151</ci:span></citefragment> <remotelink dpsi="0018" refpt="8449" remotekey1="REFPTID" service="DOC-ID"><inlineobject alttext="Click for CaseBase entry" attachment="web-server" filename="cbcc.gif" type="image"/></remotelink></ci:content></ci:cite> ; <ci:cite searchtype="CASE-REF"><ci:case><ci:caseref ID="cr000004" spanref="cr000004-001"><ci:reporter value="NSWLR"/><ci:volume num="1"/><ci:edition><ci:date year="1979"/></ci:edition><ci:page num="285"/></ci:caseref></ci:case><ci:content><citefragment searchtype="CASE-NAME-REF"><emph typestyle="it">Sherring v Goldrick</emph></citefragment><citefragment searchtype="CASE-CITE-REF"> <ci:span spanid="cr000004-001">[1979] 1 NSWLR 285</ci:span></citefragment> <remotelink dpsi="0018" refpt="82116" remotekey1="REFPTID" service="DOC-ID"><inlineobject alttext="Click for CaseBase entry" attachment="web-server" filename="cbcc.gif" type="image"/></remotelink></ci:content></ci:cite> .</text></p>
<p>
<text>Secondly, and of greater significance, on 1 January 1985 the 
<ci:cite searchtype="LEG-REF"><ci:content><remotelink dpsi="05CC" refpt="UCPN.LC.LCAN82" remotekey1="REFPTID" service="DOC-ID" status="unval">Local Courts Act, 1982</remotelink></ci:content></ci:cite>
 took effect. As from that date all Courts of Petty Sessions were abolished and were replaced  by Local Courts, presided over by a new and independent bench of magistrates replacing the stipendiary magistrates who formerly exercised jurisdiction in Courts of Petty Sessions, and who were public servants appointed under the Public Service Act. All Local  Courts were invested with the same jurisdiction, both civil and criminal, as Courts of Petty Sessions enjoyed prior to 1 January 1985. The 
<ci:cite searchtype="LEG-REF"><ci:content><remotelink dpsi="05CC" refpt="OTH.CPSCN70" remotekey1="REFPTID" service="DOC-ID" status="unval">Courts of Petty Sessions (Civil Claims) Act, 1970 </remotelink></ci:content></ci:cite>
 now became the 
<ci:cite searchtype="LEG-REF"><ci:content><remotelink dpsi="05CC" refpt="LCCN.LCA.LCCCN" remotekey1="REFPTID" service="DOC-ID" status="unval">Local Courts (Civil Claims) Act</remotelink></ci:content></ci:cite>
 .</text></p>
<p>
<text>On 1 July 1989 the 
<ci:cite searchtype="LEG-REF"><ci:content><remotelink dpsi="05CC" refpt="LCCN.LCR.LCCR" remotekey1="REFPTID" service="DOC-ID" status="unval">Local Courts (Civil Claims) Rules</remotelink></ci:content></ci:cite>
 took effect, replacing the hundred or so rules which previously operated in conjunction with the Act,  and which had little or no practical importance. The new Rules brought the Local Court into line with the rules operating in the Supreme and District Courts, and introduced an element of conformity between all three jurisdictions. They took effect on the same  day on which Sch 2 to the 
<ci:cite searchtype="LEG-REF"><ci:content><remotelink dpsi="05CC" refpt="Q.Q.Q" remotekey1="REFPTID" service="DOC-ID" status="unval">Local Courts (Civil Claims) Amendment Act 1987</remotelink></ci:content></ci:cite>
 commenced. That Schedule had the effect of removing from the Principal Act  virtually all the sections concerning procedure, which was henceforth to be governed by the Rules, thus ending that division between jurisdiction and procedure which had characterised the structure of the Act and its predecessors ever since the 
<ci:cite searchtype="LEG-REF"><ci:content><remotelink dpsi="05CC" refpt="Q.Q.Q" remotekey1="REFPTID" service="DOC-ID" status="unval">Small Debts Recovery Act of 1899</remotelink></ci:content></ci:cite>
 . I said that the new Rules had introduced a measure of conformity between the three jurisdictions. However, not all the District and Supreme Court Rules were reproduced in the Local Court counterpart.  Notable absentees were provisions relating to discovery and inspection of documents and interrogatories. Following their introduction the Rules underwent further amendment, with the object of supplementing deficiencies in the original text, importing  the District Court provisions enabling the court to dismiss an action at the close of the case for the plaintiff and to give a judgment by direction (effective 27 April 1990), enabling the Local Court to make orders for the inspection of property and for a  view (effective 31 August 1990), and providing for a Certificate of Readiness to be filed when setting a matter down for hearing (effective 1 October 1990).</text></p>
<p>
<text>There were also other legislative changes worthy of note. On 4 May 1983 the 
<ci:cite searchtype="LEG-REF"><ci:content><remotelink dpsi="05CC" refpt="LCCN.ARB.ACAAN" remotekey1="REFPTID" service="DOC-ID" status="unval">Arbitration (Civil Actions) Act 1983</remotelink></ci:content></ci:cite>
 was passed and took  effect on 1 July 1983. The Act facilitated the establishment of a scheme whereby shorter and less complicated cases might be referred for determination to arbitrators drawn from panels of practising solicitors and barristers. More than any other single factor,  this development contributed to keeping Local Court arrears in civil matters within acceptable levels, and the co-operation and assistance of the members of the private profession is to be acknowledged in this regard. Indeed, the scheme worked so well in the  District and Local Courts that on 1 January 1990, it was extended to the Supreme Court as well: 
<ci:cite searchtype="LEG-REF"><ci:content><remotelink dpsi="05CC" refpt="OTH.CRTLP" remotekey1="REFPTID" service="DOC-ID" status="unval">Courts Legislation (Procedure) Amendment Act, 1989</remotelink></ci:content></ci:cite>
 . On 6 August 1991, the arbitration system was extended by the introduction of a Philadelphia-style arbitration scheme, whereby matters are referred to a panel of arbitrators sitting on a particular day rather than to an individually nominated arbitrator as is the case with referrals made otherwise than  under the Philadelphia scheme. On 1 January 1990, 
<ci:cite searchtype="LEG-REF"><ci:content><remotelink dpsi="05CC" refpt="OTH.CRTLP.S3" remotekey1="REFPTID" service="DOC-ID" status="unval">s 3</remotelink></ci:content></ci:cite>
 and 
<ci:cite searchtype="LEG-REF"><ci:content><remotelink dpsi="05CC" refpt="OTH.CRTLP.SCH6" remotekey1="REFPTID" service="DOC-ID" status="unval">Sch 6</remotelink></ci:content></ci:cite>
 of the Courts Legislation (Procedure) Amendment Act of 1989 brought the Local Court into line with the District Court as regards the courts'  jurisdiction when a cause of action arises and/or the defendant resides outside the state. The same Act also enables execution to issue directly from the Local Court against a judgment debtor's lands where the amount required to satisfy the writ exceeds $3000  or such other amount as may be prescribed. Previously, it was necessary to have the judgment registered in the District Court and to levy execution from there.</text></p>
<p>
<text>The passing of the 
<ci:cite searchtype="LEG-REF"><ci:content><remotelink dpsi="05CC" refpt="UCPN.LC.LCAN82" remotekey1="REFPTID" service="DOC-ID" status="unval">Local Courts Act 1982</remotelink></ci:content></ci:cite>
 and the adoption of rules, which essentially mirrored the Supreme Court and in particular the District Court Rules, not only went a long way towards enhancing the status of the Local Court as a recognised third tier of the judiciary, they also provided the necessary framework and machinery for the Local Court to hear and determine civil disputes of more substantial nature. That object was realised in the first instance with the passing of the 
<ci:cite searchtype="LEG-REF"><ci:content><remotelink dpsi="05CC" refpt="Q.Q.Q" remotekey1="REFPTID" service="DOC-ID" status="unval">Courts Legislation (Civil Procedure) Amendment Act 1991</remotelink></ci:content></ci:cite>
 , which increased the court's jurisdiction to $40,000. On 1 January 2004, the court&#x2019;s pecuniary jurisdictional limit was further increased to $60,000. This was raised to $100,000 by the Courts and Crimes Legislation Further Amendment Act, No 135 of 2010, Sch 15[2], commenced 7 December 2010.</text></p>
<p>
<text>Meanwhile, on 22 November 1990, the 
<ci:cite searchtype="LEG-REF"><ci:content><remotelink dpsi="05CC" refpt="Q.Q.Q" remotekey1="REFPTID" service="DOC-ID" status="unval">Local Courts (Civil Claims) Amendment Bill of 1990</remotelink></ci:content></ci:cite>
 was introduced into Parliament. It provided for the division of Local Courts exercising jurisdiction under the Act into  two divisions, a General Division and a Small Claims Division, the latter having power to hear and determine actions where the amount involved does not exceed $3000. The Bill received assent on 13 December 1990. On 25 September 2000, this limit was increased to $190,000. The jurisdiction of the court sitting in its Small  Claims Division is exercised by assessors, appointed on a full time or part time basis, and also by magistrates. A magistrate or assessor sitting in the Small Claims Division is required  to conciliate and to bring the parties to a settlement if at all possible. Proceedings in the Division are conducted informally and the rules of evidence do not apply. A party has the right to legal representation. Costs may be awarded, but only on the default scale.</text></p>
<p>
<text>The object behind the creation of a Small Claims Division of the court was twofold. Firstly, to provide a forum where litigation over comparatively small sums may be dealt with without the full panoply, procedure and costs generally associated with  the adversarial system, and secondly to free magistrates to deal with more substantial civil and criminal disputes.</text></p>
<p>
<text>The Local Courts, or as they were formerly known, Courts of Petty Sessions, have negotiated a long road in the 160 years since they were established as Courts of Requests in 1846 with power and authority to hear and determine actions involving sums of up to £30 &#x201c;in a summary way and according to equity and good conscience&#x201d;. More recent developments, such as the Local Courts (Civil Claims) Rules 1988 and the Courts Legislation (Civil Procedure) Amendment Act, No 12 of 1991 (assented to 3 May 1991), reached fruition with the Civil Procedure Act 2005 and the Uniform Civil Procedure Rules 2005, which in matters of Civil Procedure placed the Local Court on a similar plane to the other courts exercising civil jurisdiction in the NSW judicial hierarchy.  The passing of the Local Court Act 2007, which constitutes the Local Court as a single entity exercising jurisdiction throughout the State, instead of a disparate collection of separate courts, may be seen to complete the process.</text></p>
<sigblock>
<p><text><person><name.text>Elwyn Elms</name.text></person>
<date>August 2009</date></text></p></sigblock>
</bodytext>
</level></level>
</comm:body>
</COMMENTARYDOC>