<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!DOCTYPE COMMENTARYDOC PUBLIC "-//LEXISNEXIS//DTD GLP Commentarydoc v005//EN" "commentarydoc-norm.dtd">
<COMMENTARYDOC xmlns:case="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/case" xmlns:ci="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/ci" xmlns:comm="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/comm" xmlns:cttr="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/cttr" xmlns:dict="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/dict" xmlns:dig="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/dig" xmlns:docinfo="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/docinfo" xmlns:frm="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/frm" xmlns:glp="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp" xmlns:in="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/in" xmlns:jrnl="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/jrnl" xmlns:leg="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/leg" xmlns:lnci="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnci" xmlns:lncle="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lncle" xmlns:lnclx="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnclx" xmlns:lndel="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lndel" xmlns:lndocmeta="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lndocmeta" xmlns:lngntxt="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lngntxt" xmlns:lnlit="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnlit" xmlns:lnv="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnv" xmlns:lnvni="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnvni" xmlns:lnvx="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnvx" xmlns:lnvxe="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnvxe" xmlns:nitf="urn:nitf:iptc.org.20010418.NITF" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3c.org/1999/xhtml">
<docinfo partitionnum="1"><docinfo:dpsi id-string="05CC"/><docinfo:doc-heading>District Court &#x2014; Standard Directions</docinfo:doc-heading><docinfo:doc-id>UCPN_PRACNOTE.SGM_UCPN.PN.SD</docinfo:doc-id><docinfo:doc-lang lang="en"/><docinfo:doc-country iso-cc="AU"/><docinfo:hier><docinfo:hierlev role="ancestor"><heading><title>PRACTICE NOTES</title></heading><docinfo:hierlev role="ancestor"><heading><title>District Court &#x2014; Standard Directions</title></heading><docinfo:hierlev role="me"><heading><title>District Court &#x2014; Standard Directions</title></heading></docinfo:hierlev></docinfo:hierlev></docinfo:hierlev></docinfo:hier><docinfo:bookseqnum>130570000</docinfo:bookseqnum><docinfo:lbu-meta><docinfo:metaitem name="lbu-sourcename" value="Ritchie's Uniform Civil Procedure NSW"/><docinfo:metaitem name="parent-docid" value="UCPN.PRACNOTE"/><docinfo:metaitem name="parent-filename" value="pracnote.xml"/><docinfo:metaitem name="parent-docid" value="UCPN_PRACNOTE.SGM_UCPN.PN.SD"/><docinfo:metaitem name="parent-filename" value="pracnote1114.xml"/></docinfo:lbu-meta><docinfo:selector>commentary</docinfo:selector><docinfo:load-date><date day="10" month="11" year="2011">10 November 2011</date></docinfo:load-date></docinfo>
<comm:body>
<level id="UCPN_PRACNOTE.SGM_UCPN.PN.SD" leveltype="comm.chap" subdoc="false">
<heading searchtype="COMMENTARY"><title><refpt id="UCPN.PN.SD" type="ext"/>District Court &#x2014; Standard Directions</title></heading>
<level id="UCPN_PRACNOTE.SGM_UCPN.PN.SD.159995" leveltype="para0" subdoc="true" toc-caption="[159,995]"><heading searchtype="COMMENTARY"><edpnum><refpt id="UCPN.PN.SD.159995" type="ext"/>[159,995] </edpnum></heading>
<bodytext searchtype="COMMENTARY">
<p>
<text>Several of the District Court practice notes contemplate directions being made at an early stage of the proceedings. (These provisions include, for example, DC (Civil) 1 at [5.6] and [11.1]; DC (Civil) 2 at [5].) Some practice notes specifically contemplate that standard directions may be made in particular types of proceedings: for example, DC (Civil) 6 at [5]. </text></p>
<p>
<text>Some practice notes specifically contemplate dismissal of proceedings, or the striking out of documents, where parties fail to comply with directions: for example, DC (Civil) 1 at [2.5]. The practice notes contemplate the court making &#x201c;show cause&#x201d; orders in the case of a party&#x2019;s failure to comply with court directions: for example, DC (Civil) 1 at [8.5], [11.3]. </text></p>
<p>
<text>The following standard directions reflect the practice of the District Court in relation to the specific directions commonly made in the situations to which each of the following paragraphs refer. In the form in which they are reproduced here the contents of the directions are generic descriptions of the substance of the directions. However, all litigants and their legal representatives should appreciate that when these matters are actually included in the directions made in their particular matters, they take effect as orders of the court and should be complied with accordingly.</text></p>
</bodytext>
</level><level id="UCPN_PRACNOTE.SGM_UCPN.PN.SD.160000" leveltype="para0" subdoc="true" toc-caption="[DC SD 1] Hearings and arbitrations"><heading searchtype="COMMENTARY"><edpnum><refpt id="UCPN.PN.SD.160000" type="ext"/>[DC SD 1] </edpnum><title>Hearings and arbitrations</title></heading>
<bodytext searchtype="COMMENTARY">
<p>
<text>Prior to the hearing date the following will be required to be carried out: </text></p>
<pgrp>
<heading><title>Chronology</title></heading>
<p>
<text>Plaintiff's solicitor is to prepare a full chronology of relevant events, a copy of which is to be served upon the other party/parties at least three clear days prior to the hearing date. </text></p>
<p>
<text>The plaintiff is to read the chronology <emph typestyle="bf">before giving evidence</emph> as the chronology will be made an exhibit and the plaintiff may be cross-examined on its contents. </text></p></pgrp>
<pgrp>
<heading><title>Medical and expert reports</title></heading>
<p>
<text>Each party is to prepare a schedule of medical and expert reports and any other documents which are to be tendered and a copy of the schedule is to be served upon the other party/parties at least three days prior to the hearing. </text></p>
<p>
<text>The schedule is to contain the dates of the reports and the dates of service.</text></p>
<p>
<text>Working copies of all medical reports, the chronology and all other documents which any party proposes to tender should be available for the trial judge. </text></p></pgrp>
<pgrp>
<heading><title>Schedule of damages and issues</title></heading>
<p>
<text>Each party is to prepare a schedule of damages and a schedule of issues which is to be served upon the other party/parties at least three days prior to the hearing date and copies of those schedules are to be provided to the trial judge. </text></p></pgrp>
<pgrp>
<heading><title>Adjournments</title></heading>
<p>
<text>All cases should be ready to proceed on the hearing date. Adjournments will only be granted in exceptional circumstances.</text></p>
<p>
<text>Any application for an adjournment must be made by way of Notice of Motion with affidavit in support and must be made at the earliest possible time.</text></p></pgrp>
</bodytext>
</level><level id="UCPN_PRACNOTE.SGM_UCPN.PN.SD.160010" leveltype="para0" subdoc="true" toc-caption="[DC SD 2] Case Managed List show cause hearings"><heading searchtype="COMMENTARY"><edpnum><refpt id="UCPN.PN.SD.160010" type="ext"/>[DC SD 2] </edpnum><title>Case Managed List show cause hearings</title></heading>
<bodytext searchtype="COMMENTARY">
<p>
<text>This matter has been listed for directions: </text>
<l>
<li>
<lilabel>&#x2022;</lilabel>
<p><text>For the plaintiff to show cause why the action should not be dismissed for want of prosecution</text></p></li>
<li>
<lilabel>&#x2022;</lilabel>
<p><text>For the defendant to show cause why the defence should not be struck out and/or any cross claim dismissed for want of prosecution. </text></p></li></l></p>
<p>
<text><emph typestyle="bf">All parties are reminded that this is a very serious matter.</emph></text></p>
<p>
<text>The Court makes the following orders, which must be strictly complied with: </text></p>
<pgrp>
<heading><title>Order 1</title></heading>
<p>
<text>At least five days before the directions hearing, the legal practitioner for the party in default (or the party, if self-represented) must file and serve an affidavit setting out the reasons why he or she has not complied with the court orders and/or 
<remotelink dpsi="05CC" refpt="UCPN.PN.DC1" remotekey1="REFPTID" service="DOC-ID">Practice Note 1</remotelink>
. You must file this affidavit even if you are ready to take a hearing date at the directions hearing. </text></p>
<p>
<text>Please note:</text>
<l>
<li>
<lilabel>a)</lilabel>
<p><text>The affidavit must show that the party ordered to show cause is personally aware that the court is considering dismissing their action or cross claim or striking out their defence</text></p></li>
<li>
<lilabel>b)</lilabel>
<p><text>The solicitor for a plaintiff in default must satisfy the court that the action was not commenced in contravention of 
<remotelink dpsi="05CC" refpt="UCPN.PN.DC1" remotekey1="REFPTID" service="DOC-ID">Practice Note 1</remotelink></text></p></li>
<li>
<lilabel>c)</lilabel>
<p><text>Your attention is drawn to clause 2.1 of 
<remotelink dpsi="05CC" refpt="UCPN.PN.DC1" remotekey1="REFPTID" service="DOC-ID">Practice Note 1</remotelink>
 and the reference to special circumstances</text></p></li>
<li>
<lilabel>d)</lilabel>
<p><text>It may be necessary to annex medical evidence to the affidavit.</text></p></li></l></p></pgrp>
<pgrp>
<heading><title>Order 2</title></heading>
<p>
<text>Where a legal practitioner is on record for a party, the solicitor with conduct of the action or counsel who holds the brief must represent that party at the directions hearing and have instructions sufficient to assist the court to make all appropriate orders and directions. </text></p>
<p>
<text>It is essential that the party asked to show cause be so represented and it is inappropriate for that practitioner to ask the representative of another party to mention his or her appearance. It is generally inappropriate for a clerk or an agent to appear at a show cause hearing. </text></p></pgrp>
<pgrp>
<heading><title>Order 3</title></heading>
<p>
<text>Any party who wishes the court to consider any submissions supporting dismissal must put those submissions in writing, file and serve them at least 5 days before the directions hearing. </text></p></pgrp>
<pgrp>
<heading><title>Order 4</title></heading>
<p>
<text>Except in special circumstances, the court will not accept or consider any affidavit or submissions it has not received before the directions hearing. </text></p></pgrp>
</bodytext>
</level><level id="UCPN_PRACNOTE.SGM_UCPN.PN.SD.160020" leveltype="para0" subdoc="true" toc-caption="[DC SD 3] Commercial List default order "><heading searchtype="COMMENTARY"><edpnum><refpt id="UCPN.PN.SD.160020" type="ext"/>[DC SD 3] </edpnum><title>Commercial List default order </title></heading>
<bodytext searchtype="COMMENTARY">
<p>
<l>
<li>
<lilabel>(a)</lilabel>
<p><text>In the event that a party fails to comply with any order made today for a period of more than seven days then the solicitor for the defaulting party must immediately apply to have the matter listed for mention before the Commercial List Judge.</text></p>
<p><text>Such application shall be made by facsimile transmission addressed to Associate to His Honour Judge Rolfe (9377 5777) and shall have attached to it an affidavit by the solicitor stating the reasons for the default and that the defaulting party has notified the other party or parties that the application for re-listing has been made. </text></p></li>
<li>
<lilabel>(b)</lilabel>
<p><text>If the defaulting party fails to comply with Order (a) above, the other party or parties must then apply to have the matter restored before the Commercial List Judge for mention.</text></p></li></l></p>
</bodytext>
</level></level>
</comm:body>
</COMMENTARYDOC>