<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!DOCTYPE CASEDOC PUBLIC "-//LEXISNEXIS//DTD GLP Casedoc v005//EN" "casedoc-norm.dtd">
<CASEDOC type="fulltext" xmlns:case="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/case" xmlns:ci="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/ci" xmlns:comm="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/comm" xmlns:cttr="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/cttr" xmlns:dict="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/dict" xmlns:dig="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/dig" xmlns:docinfo="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/docinfo" xmlns:frm="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/frm" xmlns:glp="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp" xmlns:in="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/in" xmlns:jrnl="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/jrnl" xmlns:leg="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/leg" xmlns:lnci="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnci" xmlns:lncle="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lncle" xmlns:lnclx="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnclx" xmlns:lndel="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lndel" xmlns:lndocmeta="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lndocmeta" xmlns:lngntxt="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lngntxt" xmlns:lnlit="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnlit" xmlns:lnv="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnv" xmlns:lnvni="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnvni" xmlns:lnvx="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnvx" xmlns:lnvxe="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnvxe" xmlns:nitf="urn:nitf:iptc.org.20010418.NITF" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3c.org/1999/xhtml">
<docinfo partitionnum="3"><docinfo:dpsi id-string="05CC"/><docinfo:doc-heading>[456,120] EXLEY v WYONG SHIRE COUNCIL</docinfo:doc-heading><docinfo:doc-id>UCPN_PRACDEC.SGM_UCPN.PRACDEC.456120</docinfo:doc-id><docinfo:doc-lang lang="en"/><docinfo:doc-country iso-cc="AU"/><docinfo:hier><docinfo:hierlev role="ancestor"><heading><title>PRACTICE DECISIONS</title></heading><docinfo:hierlev role="ancestor"><heading><title>PRACTICE DECISIONS</title></heading><docinfo:hierlev role="me"><heading><edpnum>[456,120]</edpnum><title>EXLEY v WYONG SHIRE COUNCIL</title></heading></docinfo:hierlev></docinfo:hierlev></docinfo:hierlev></docinfo:hier><docinfo:bookseqnum>160030000</docinfo:bookseqnum><docinfo:lbu-meta><docinfo:metaitem name="lbu-sourcename" value="Ritchie's Uniform Civil Procedure NSW"/><docinfo:metaitem name="parent-docid" value="UCPN.PRACDEC"/><docinfo:metaitem name="parent-filename" value="pracdec.xml"/><docinfo:metaitem name="parent-docid" value="UCPN_PRACDEC.SGM_UCPN.PRACDEC.456120"/><docinfo:metaitem name="parent-filename" value="pracdec1006.xml"/></docinfo:lbu-meta><docinfo:selector>case</docinfo:selector><docinfo:load-date><date day="11" month="09" year="2012">11 September 2012</date></docinfo:load-date></docinfo>
<case:body><heading searchtype="PRACTICE-NOTE"><edpnum><refpt id="UCPN.PRACDEC.456120" type="ext"/>[456,120]</edpnum></heading>
<case:headnote>
<case:info><case:casename searchtype="PRACTICE-NOTE">EXLEY v WYONG SHIRE COUNCIL</case:casename></case:info>
<case:info>
<case:courtinfo><case:courtname>Supreme Court NSW</case:courtname>
<case:judges><case:judge>Master Allen</case:judge>
</case:judges><case:dates><case:decisiondate>10 December 1976</case:decisiondate></case:dates>
<case:filenum>CL No 6277/76 &#x2014; Noted [1977] ACLD 027</case:filenum>
</case:courtinfo></case:info><catchwordgrp><catchwords><catchphrase>UCPR r 5 &#x2013; [SCR Pt 3]</catchphrase><catchphrase>Preliminary discovery and inspection</catchphrase></catchwords>
</catchwordgrp></case:headnote><case:content>
<case:judgments><case:judgment><case:courtinfo><case:judges><case:judge>Master Allen</case:judge></case:judges></case:courtinfo>
<case:judgmentbody>
<p>
<text>Part 3 r 1 was amended following the decision of Master Cantor, as he then was, in <ci:cite searchtype="CASE-REF"><ci:case><ci:caseref ID="cr000039" spanref="cr000039-001"><ci:reporter value="NSWLR"/><ci:volume num="1"/><ci:edition><ci:date year="1973"/></ci:edition><ci:page num="52"/></ci:caseref></ci:case><ci:content><citefragment searchtype="CASE-NAME-REF"><emph typestyle="it">Taylor v Osborne</emph></citefragment><citefragment searchtype="CASE-CITE-REF"> <ci:span spanid="cr000039-001">[1973] 1 NSWLR 52</ci:span></citefragment> <remotelink dpsi="0018" refpt="79612" remotekey1="REFPTID" service="DOC-ID"><inlineobject alttext="Click for CaseBase entry" attachment="web-server" filename="cbcc.gif" type="image"/></remotelink></ci:content></ci:cite>. In that case the Master held that the requirements of the rule, in its then form, were not satisfied unless the applicant for preliminary discovery established that he had a prima facie case for relief against a particular person albeit that he did not know the name (or other adequate description) of that particular person. The Master said: &#x201c;The rule as drawn does not authorize, in my opinion, an applicant embarking upon a fishing expedition to identify persons against whom he has not established a prima facie case for relief&#x201d; (at 56). The rule, in its present form, makes no reference to it being shown that the plaintiff has a prima facie case for relief against the unidentified person. Instead, it provides, so far as relevant, that the court may order preliminary discovery where it appears that &#x201c;the applicant, having made reasonable enquiries, is unable to ascertain the identity of the person for the purpose of commencing proceedings against that person or is unable to ascertain the description of any person sufficiently for that purpose&#x201d;. But, as Mr White has pointed out, the granting of preliminary discovery is within the discretion of the court. In that regard, in my opinion a material factor is the prospect of the plaintiff succeeding in proceedings against the person whom he wishes to sue once he has obtained his name. The provision made by Pt 3 for preliminary discovery was a bold innovation although, to some extent, the same objective has been attained in England by application of the principles applicable to the Old Bill of Discovery in Equity and a specific rule in personal injury cases (O 24 r 7A). The objective was to overcome the manifest injustice which could occur that a person who had suffered a legal wrong committed by another might be without redress because he did not know the name of the wrongdoer or otherwise have such a description of his identity as would enable him to be sued. In such a case it was only just that the person so wronged should be enabled to obtain the wrongdoer's name (or other appropriate identification) from a person who had that knowledge. Preliminary discovery is a valuable aid to justice. But its objective would be perverted if it were to be permitted to be turned into an instrument of oppression. In my opinion it would be turned into an instrument of oppression if it became a procedure in aid of speculative claims. It is one thing to require the name of a wrongdoer to be disclosed to the person wronged. It is a very different thing to require his name to be disclosed so that someone supposing himself to have a grievance against him may commence merely speculative proceedings against him. This does not mean that an applicant for preliminary discovery will never be granted that relief unless he establishes that he has a prima facie case against the person whose name he wishes to ascertain. The evidence, although falling short of establishing all the ingredients of a prima facie case, may point sufficiently to the existence of a case for relief as to make it proper, in the interests of justice, that preliminary discovery be ordered so that proceedings for that relief can be brought. Each case must be considered on its own merits.</text></p></case:judgmentbody></case:judgment>
</case:judgments>
</case:content>
</case:body></CASEDOC>