<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!DOCTYPE CASEDOC PUBLIC "-//LEXISNEXIS//DTD GLP Casedoc v005//EN" "casedoc-norm.dtd">
<CASEDOC type="fulltext" xmlns:case="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/case" xmlns:ci="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/ci" xmlns:comm="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/comm" xmlns:cttr="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/cttr" xmlns:dict="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/dict" xmlns:dig="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/dig" xmlns:docinfo="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/docinfo" xmlns:frm="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/frm" xmlns:glp="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp" xmlns:in="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/in" xmlns:jrnl="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/jrnl" xmlns:leg="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/leg" xmlns:lnci="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnci" xmlns:lncle="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lncle" xmlns:lnclx="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnclx" xmlns:lndel="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lndel" xmlns:lndocmeta="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lndocmeta" xmlns:lngntxt="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lngntxt" xmlns:lnlit="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnlit" xmlns:lnv="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnv" xmlns:lnvni="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnvni" xmlns:lnvx="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnvx" xmlns:lnvxe="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnvxe" xmlns:nitf="urn:nitf:iptc.org.20010418.NITF" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3c.org/1999/xhtml">
<docinfo partitionnum="3"><docinfo:dpsi id-string="05CC"/><docinfo:doc-heading>[456,140] HILLS v KING</docinfo:doc-heading><docinfo:doc-id>UCPN_PRACDEC.SGM_UCPN.PRACDEC.456140</docinfo:doc-id><docinfo:doc-lang lang="en"/><docinfo:doc-country iso-cc="AU"/><docinfo:hier><docinfo:hierlev role="ancestor"><heading><title>PRACTICE DECISIONS</title></heading><docinfo:hierlev role="ancestor"><heading><title>PRACTICE DECISIONS</title></heading><docinfo:hierlev role="me"><heading><edpnum>[456,140]</edpnum><title>HILLS v KING</title></heading></docinfo:hierlev></docinfo:hierlev></docinfo:hierlev></docinfo:hier><docinfo:bookseqnum>160070000</docinfo:bookseqnum><docinfo:lbu-meta><docinfo:metaitem name="lbu-sourcename" value="Ritchie's Uniform Civil Procedure NSW"/><docinfo:metaitem name="parent-docid" value="UCPN.PRACDEC"/><docinfo:metaitem name="parent-filename" value="pracdec.xml"/><docinfo:metaitem name="parent-docid" value="UCPN_PRACDEC.SGM_UCPN.PRACDEC.456140"/><docinfo:metaitem name="parent-filename" value="pracdec1014.xml"/></docinfo:lbu-meta><docinfo:selector>case</docinfo:selector><docinfo:load-date><date day="11" month="09" year="2012">11 September 2012</date></docinfo:load-date></docinfo>
<case:body><heading searchtype="PRACTICE-NOTE"><edpnum><refpt id="UCPN.PRACDEC.456140" type="ext"/>[456,140]</edpnum></heading>
<case:headnote>
<case:info><case:casename searchtype="PRACTICE-NOTE">HILLS v KING</case:casename></case:info>
<case:info>
<case:courtinfo><case:courtname>Local Court of New South Wales, Sydney</case:courtname>
<case:judges><case:judge>Elms M</case:judge>
</case:judges><case:dates><case:decisiondate>5 September 1988</case:decisiondate></case:dates>
<case:filenum>No 14041/88</case:filenum>
</case:courtinfo></case:info><catchwordgrp><catchwords><catchphrase>Jurisdiction</catchphrase><catchphrase>Local Courts (Civil Claims) Act, s 12</catchphrase><catchphrase>Local Court has no jurisdiction to exercise equitable powers or grant equitable remedies, however it does have jurisdiction to entertain common law claim for damages following alleged repudiation of lease agreement.</catchphrase></catchwords>
</catchwordgrp></case:headnote><case:content>
<case:judgments><case:judgment><case:courtinfo><case:judges><case:judge>Elms M</case:judge></case:judges></case:courtinfo>
<case:judgmentbody>
<p>
<text>The question to be determined at this stage of the proceedings is whether the court has jurisdiction to entertain the plaint.</text></p>
<p>
<text>By its particulars of claim filed 18 April 1988, the plaintiffs assert that they leased the premises 8 Ethell Road, Kirrawee to the defendant for a period of two (2) years commencing on 1 December 1985 and terminating 30 November 1987. The lease contained an option clause and, according to para 3 of the particulars filed &#x201c;by written request dated 24 September 1987, the defendant exercised the option of renewal for a further term of two (2) years from 1 December 1987 to 30 November 1989&#x201d;, which was accepted by the plaintiffs and negotiations commenced between plaintiffs and defendant as to the then current market rental value of the premises. No agreement being reached, the plaintiffs, by their agent, proposed to invoke para 20(i) of the lease, which broadly sets out a procedure for the rental to be determined by a valuer in the event of the parties being unable to reach agreement. By letter of 4 November 1987, the defendant purported to withdraw his exercise which was not accepted by the plaintiffs, and the defendant subsequently vacated the premises on 30 November 1987, &#x201c;and failed or refused to enter into a lease for the renewed term&#x201d;. The plaintiffs &#x201c;in order to mitigate (their) loss&#x201d; leased the premises to another tenant pursuant to a lease commencing 1 January 1988. The plaintiffs assert that they have suffered damage by reason of the premises being vacant for the month of December 1987, and claim loss of rent for the month of December and agents' commission payable for the procuring of another tenant.</text></p>
<p>
<text>By his defence, the defendant admits paras 1 and 2 of the plaintiffs' particulars. He &#x201c;does not admit&#x201d; any other paragraph of those particulars, and says in relation to para 3 &#x201c;that the option for renewal was not exercisable on 24 September 1987 having lapsed according to its terms on or before 1 September 1987.&#x201d; He says that &#x201c;although during the period 24 September 1987 to 4 November 1987, the plaintiffs and the defendant entered into negotiations for the further lease of the premises no agreement was ever reached.&#x201d; I leave aside the issue as to whether those grounds of defence constitute proper grounds of defence to an action initiated by way of plaint and default summons.</text></p>
<p>
<text>The matter was listed for hearing at this court on 26 August 1988 for the defendant to argue a point of jurisdiction. By his counsel he argued that the Local Court had no jurisdiction in the matter, because it would in effect be exercising equitable powers and granting equitable remedies in the event that it returned a verdict in favour of the plaintiffs. To do so, said Mr Powell, I would have to declare that there was an enforceable option or an agreement to enter into a lease. Alternatively, I would be decreeing notional specific performance of that lease. These proceedings must be postponed, he said, until after the plaintiffs have sought a declaration that there is a valid and enforceable agreement to enter into a lease. Only then, said Mr Powell, can the court award &#x201c;rent&#x201d; under the lease. If the court awards &#x201c;rent&#x201d; it is implicitly finding that the alleged agreement to enter into the lease was enforceable, and it can only be enforceable according to equitable doctrines. The Local Court would therefore be exercising equitable jurisdiction and this it cannot do.</text></p>
<p>
<text>Mr Reynolds, on the other hand, argued on behalf of the plaintiffs that the plaintiffs' only claim was for damages, and that the Local Court certainly has jurisdiction to entertain a claim for damages. Neither the finding of fact that there was an agreement between the parties, nor the award of damages consequent upon the breach thereof involve the exercise of equitable jurisdictions nor equitable remedies. Section 29(1)  of the Local Courts (Civil Claims) Act, 1970 contains a limitation of the court's jurisdiction where the title to land is in question. No question involving the title to land arises here, said Mr Reynolds, since the question of the existence or non-existence of a lease or an agreement to lease is not a question involving the title to land, but even if it is it only arises incidentally and therefore the court would still have jurisdiction under s 19(2) of the Act.</text></p>
<p>
<text>I have considered the arguments advanced by Mr Powell very carefully, but I am afraid that I cannot agree with them. Section 12(1) of the Local Courts (Civil Claims) Act, 1970, so far as is here relevant, gives the court jurisdiction to &#x201c;hear and determine actions for the recovery of any debt, demand or damage, whether liquidated or unliquidated &#x2026; in which the amount claimed is not more than $10,000 &#x2026;,&#x201d; and by its very terms para 8 of the particulars of claim asserts that &#x201c;the plaintiff has suffered damage by reason of the premises being vacant for the month of December 1987&#x201d;. The plaintiffs' claim, as I see it, is, on the face of the pleadings, purely one for damages, and damages simpliciter is a common law remedy. A court of equity also has power to award damages as an incident of, or ancillary to, or in lieu of, its powers to grant other relief, such as specific performance. However, in the circumstances of this case, I cannot agree that by hearing and determining the plaintiffs' claim for damages (in the terms of s 12(1) of the Act), the court is notionally enforcing (that is, granting specific performance of) the lease. Specific performance simply does not arise because, again on the face of the pleadings, and making no determination of the factual issues which the court has to decide at a later stage, the plaintiffs have accepted the defendant's repudiation of their alleged agreement. They have relet the premises and sued for their alleged loss during the month of December, plus a claim for agent's commission. The claim therefore is one for damages simpliciter, notwithstanding the terms &#x201c;rent&#x201d; and &#x201c;commission&#x201d; which appear in the particulars, and findings of fact that there was an agreement and a breach thereof, are not in my view tantamount to decreeing specific performance of an agreement to lease which the plaintiffs accept is now at an end.</text></p>
<p>
<text>The defendant's submissions would have far more force if the plaintiff were asserting that the lease agreement was extant, and if the tenant's alleged repudiation of the option arrangements on termination of the agreement to lease had not been accepted. By &#x201c;accepted&#x201d; I do not mean to imply that the plaintiff consented to the repudiation, or rather the alleged repudiation, simply that he accepted what has occurred as a fait accompli, and took steps to minimise his damage. This was the situation in <ci:cite searchtype="CASE-REF"><ci:case><ci:caseref ID="cr000057" spanref="cr000057-001" status="unval"><ci:reporter value="SASR"/><ci:edition><ci:date year="1929"/></ci:edition><ci:page num="274"/></ci:caseref></ci:case><ci:content><citefragment searchtype="CASE-NAME-REF"><emph typestyle="it">Moore v Dimond</emph></citefragment><citefragment searchtype="CASE-CITE-REF"> <ci:span spanid="cr000057-001" status="unval">[1929] SASR 274</ci:span></citefragment> <remotelink dpsi="0018" refpt="116739" remotekey1="REFPTID" service="DOC-ID"><inlineobject alttext="Click for CaseBase entry" attachment="web-server" filename="cbcc.gif" type="image"/></remotelink></ci:content></ci:cite> and <ci:cite searchtype="CASE-REF"><ci:case><ci:caseref ID="cr000058" spanref="cr000058-001" status="unval"><ci:reporter value="QB"/><ci:volume num="2"/><ci:edition><ci:date year="1892"/></ci:edition><ci:page num="255"/></ci:caseref></ci:case><ci:content><citefragment searchtype="CASE-NAME-REF"><emph typestyle="it">Foster v Reeves</emph></citefragment><citefragment searchtype="CASE-CITE-REF"> <ci:span spanid="cr000058-001" status="unval">[1892] 2 QB 255</ci:span></citefragment> <remotelink dpsi="0018" refpt="4390" remotekey1="REFPTID" service="DOC-ID"><inlineobject alttext="Click for CaseBase entry" attachment="web-server" filename="cbcc.gif" type="image"/></remotelink></ci:content></ci:cite>. The plaintiffs' claim would then consist of an equitable claim for rent under the lease and not for damages, and a court adjudicating upon such a claim in favour of the plaintiff would in effect be enforcing the lease, which is an equitable remedy beyond the jurisdiction of the Local Court.</text></p>
<p>
<text>Nor is the plaintiffs' claim one for &#x201c;equitable damages&#x201d;, that is damages claimed in a competent court exercising equitable jurisdiction in lieu of specific performance, as it was in <ci:cite searchtype="CASE-REF"><ci:case><ci:caseinfo><ci:decisiondate year="1909"/></ci:caseinfo><ci:caseref ID="cr000059" spanref="cr000059-001" status="unval"><ci:reporter value="SALR"/><ci:page num="28"/></ci:caseref></ci:case><ci:content><citefragment searchtype="CASE-NAME-REF"><emph typestyle="it">Douglas v Hill</emph></citefragment><citefragment searchtype="CASE-CITE-REF"> <ci:span spanid="cr000059-001" status="unval">(1909) SALR 28</ci:span></citefragment></ci:content></ci:cite>, where the court held that the equitable doctrine of part performance applied in relation to an oral agreement relating to an interest in land. The court held that the agreement was one which a Court of Equity could have specifically enforced, and that the plaintiff was quite entitled to sue in the Local Court for damages in lieu of specific performance. That decision is based upon s 33 of the Local Court Act (SA) 1886 which is couched in substantially similar terms to s 5 of the Law Reform (Law and Equity) Act 1972, and provides that in the event that there is any conflict between the rules of equity and the rules of common law, the former shall prevail. The decision is therefore of limited applicability in New South Wales following <ci:cite searchtype="CASE-REF"><ci:case><ci:caseinfo><ci:decisiondate year="1975"/></ci:caseinfo><ci:caseref ID="cr000060" spanref="cr000060-001" status="unval"><ci:reporter value="BPR"/><ci:volume num="1"/><ci:page num="9642"/></ci:caseref></ci:case><ci:content><citefragment searchtype="CASE-NAME-REF"><emph typestyle="it">Joblin v Carney</emph></citefragment><citefragment searchtype="CASE-CITE-REF"> <ci:span spanid="cr000060-001" status="unval">(1975) 1 BPR 9642</ci:span></citefragment> <remotelink dpsi="0018" refpt="213431" remotekey1="REFPTID" service="DOC-ID"><inlineobject alttext="Click for CaseBase entry" attachment="web-server" filename="cbcc.gif" type="image"/></remotelink></ci:content></ci:cite> see [16,015], where Glass JA held that the provisions of s 5 are directed only to those courts invested with jurisdiction to administer both systems of law.</text></p>
<p>
<text>The point is, however, that on the face of the pleadings, this is not a &#x201c;claim to the rent which may be payable as an equitable debt under the agreement for a lease, if any such agreement exists&#x201d; (<emph typestyle="it">Moore v Dimond</emph>, 
<fnr fnrtoken="SMN.PRACDEC.190180.FTN1-R" fntoken="SMN.PRACDEC.190180.FTN1">1</fnr>above at 282 ), nor is it a claim for &#x201c;equitable damages&#x201d; in lieu of specific performance, as it was in <emph typestyle="it">Douglas v Hill</emph>, 
<fnr fnrtoken="SMN.PRACDEC.190180.FTN2-R" fntoken="SMN.PRACDEC.190180.FTN2">2</fnr>above. It is a claim for damages following the alleged breach of an agreement to lease which the Local Court has jurisdiction to hear and determine pursuant to s 12 of the Act.</text></p>
<p>
<text>In coming to this decision, I have considered the authorities cited by Mr Powell, <emph typestyle="it">Moore v Dimond</emph>
<fnr fnrtoken="SMN.PRACDEC.190180.FTN3-R" fntoken="SMN.PRACDEC.190180.FTN3">3</fnr> and <ci:cite searchtype="CASE-REF"><ci:case><ci:caseinfo><ci:decisiondate year="1975"/></ci:caseinfo><ci:caseref ID="cr000063" spanref="cr000063-001" status="unval"><ci:reporter value="BPR"/><ci:volume num="1"/><ci:page num="9642"/></ci:caseref></ci:case><ci:content><citefragment searchtype="CASE-NAME-REF"><emph typestyle="it">Joblin v Carney</emph></citefragment><citefragment searchtype="CASE-CITE-REF"> <ci:span spanid="cr000063-001" status="unval">(1975) 1 BPR 9642</ci:span></citefragment> <remotelink dpsi="0018" refpt="213431" remotekey1="REFPTID" service="DOC-ID"><inlineobject alttext="Click for CaseBase entry" attachment="web-server" filename="cbcc.gif" type="image"/></remotelink></ci:content></ci:cite> together with a number of authorities cited in <emph typestyle="it">Moore v Dimond</emph>;
<fnr fnrtoken="SMN.PRACDEC.190180.FTN4-R" fntoken="SMN.PRACDEC.190180.FTN4">4</fnr> <ci:cite searchtype="CASE-REF"><ci:case><ci:caseinfo><ci:decisiondate year="1885"/></ci:caseinfo><ci:caseref ID="cr000064" spanref="cr000064-001" status="unval"><ci:reporter value="SALR"/><ci:volume num="19"/><ci:page num="69"/></ci:caseref></ci:case><ci:content><citefragment searchtype="CASE-NAME-REF"><emph typestyle="it">Shaw v Baker</emph></citefragment><citefragment searchtype="CASE-CITE-REF"> <ci:span spanid="cr000064-001" status="unval">(1885) 19 SALR 69</ci:span></citefragment> <remotelink dpsi="0018" refpt="115522" remotekey1="REFPTID" service="DOC-ID"><inlineobject alttext="Click for CaseBase entry" attachment="web-server" filename="cbcc.gif" type="image"/></remotelink></ci:content></ci:cite>; <emph typestyle="it">Douglas v Hill</emph>,
<fnr fnrtoken="SMN.PRACDEC.190180.FTN5-R" fntoken="SMN.PRACDEC.190180.FTN5">5</fnr> above and <emph typestyle="it">Foster v Reeves</emph>, 
<fnr fnrtoken="SMN.PRACDEC.190180.FTN6-R" fntoken="SMN.PRACDEC.190180.FTN6">6</fnr>above. Those cases make clear, I feel, the distinction I have endeavoured to make above &#x2014; between on the one hand, an equitable claim for rent pursuant to an agreement which the plaintiffs claim is extant (see, for example, <emph typestyle="it">Foster v Reeves</emph>)
<fnr fnrtoken="SMN.PRACDEC.190180.FTN7-R" fntoken="SMN.PRACDEC.190180.FTN7">7</fnr> and a claim for damages on the basis of an agreement, which the plaintiffs accept is now at an end, on the other; between an equitable claim for damages in lieu of specific performance which could have been awarded but was not, and a common law claim for damages.</text></p>
<p>
<text>In hearing and determining the plaintiffs' claim for damages in this case, a court is not assuming &#x201c;authority to adjust the rights of contracting parties where we are satisfied that a court of equity would interfere to reform according to the real intention at the time of making the contract&#x201d;, as the Local Court purported to do in <emph typestyle="it">Shaw v Baker</emph>, 
<fnr fnrtoken="SMN.PRACDEC.190180.FTN8-R" fntoken="SMN.PRACDEC.190180.FTN8">8</fnr>above at 72. Nor is the court attempting to superimpose some artificial equitable doctrine, such as the rule in <ci:cite searchtype="CASE-REF"><ci:case><ci:caseinfo><ci:decisiondate year="1852"/></ci:caseinfo><ci:caseref ID="cr000067" spanref="cr000067-001" status="unval"><ci:reporter value="HLCas"/><ci:volume num="3"/><ci:page num="565"/></ci:caseref><ci:caseref ID="cr000068" spanref="cr000068-002" status="unval"><ci:reporter value="ER"/><ci:volume num="10"/><ci:page num="222"/></ci:caseref></ci:case><ci:content><citefragment searchtype="CASE-NAME-REF"><emph typestyle="it">Birch v Joy</emph></citefragment><citefragment searchtype="CASE-CITE-REF"> <ci:span spanid="cr000067-001" status="unval">(1852) 3 HL Cas 565</ci:span>; <ci:span spanid="cr000068-002" status="unval">10 ER 222</ci:span></citefragment> <remotelink dpsi="0018" refpt="26959" remotekey1="REFPTID" service="DOC-ID"><inlineobject alttext="Click for CaseBase entry" attachment="web-server" filename="cbcc.gif" type="image"/></remotelink></ci:content></ci:cite>, upon the parties' contractual arrangements as the District Court Judge erroneously attempted to do in <ci:cite searchtype="CASE-REF"><ci:case><ci:caseinfo><ci:decisiondate year="1975"/></ci:caseinfo><ci:caseref ID="cr000069" spanref="cr000069-001" status="unval"><ci:reporter value="BPR"/><ci:volume num="1"/><ci:page num="9642"/></ci:caseref></ci:case><ci:content><citefragment searchtype="CASE-NAME-REF"><emph typestyle="it">Joblin v Carney</emph></citefragment><citefragment searchtype="CASE-CITE-REF"> <ci:span spanid="cr000069-001" status="unval">(1975) 1 BPR 9642</ci:span></citefragment> <remotelink dpsi="0018" refpt="213431" remotekey1="REFPTID" service="DOC-ID"><inlineobject alttext="Click for CaseBase entry" attachment="web-server" filename="cbcc.gif" type="image"/></remotelink></ci:content></ci:cite>. Finally this is not a case where any question of the postponement of relief under s 7 of the Law Reform (Law and Equity) Act of 1972 arises, since the Local Court is not here asked to make an order for specific performance, either notionally or otherwise. Compare the passage cited by Mr Powell in Meagher, Gummow and Lehane, <emph typestyle="it">Equity: Doctrines &amp; Remedies</emph> 2nd ed, Butterworths, 1984 at [249].</text></p>
<p>
<text>In summary, therefore, the plaintiffs' claim as I see it on the face of the pleadings, is a common law claim for damages. It is not a claim for an &#x201c;equitable debt&#x201d; as in <emph typestyle="it">Foster v Reeves</emph>,
<fnr fnrtoken="SMN.PRACDEC.190180.FTN9-R" fntoken="SMN.PRACDEC.190180.FTN9">9</fnr> nor a claim for &#x201c;equitable damages&#x201d; as in <emph typestyle="it">Douglas v Hill</emph>.
<fnr fnrtoken="SMN.PRACDEC.190180.FTN10-R" fntoken="SMN.PRACDEC.190180.FTN10">10</fnr> I therefore hold that the Local Court has jurisdiction.</text></p>
<p>
<text>There are two comments I would like to make by way of conclusion. Both might appear obvious. The first is that I have as yet heard no evidence. The plaintiffs might fail to prove any agreement such as that alleged. It would therefore be somewhat premature, in my view, for this court to decline to exercise jurisdiction before it has made findings of fact. If during the course of the evidence, some difficulty arises whereby the court finds itself confronted with the problem of being asked to apply equitable doctrines or equitable remedies &#x2014; and the possibility of a lack of coincidence between pleadings and evidence is there, since Local Courts are not courts of strict pleading &#x2014; the issue of jurisdiction can be further confronted at that stage.</text></p>
<p>
<text>The second comment I would like to make is that nothing I have said should be taken to suggest that I have formed any view as to either party's ultimate chances of success in this action, a matter upon which I have as yet had no evidence, let alone argument.</text></p>
<glp:note>
<h>Editor's note:</h>
<p>
<text>In addition to the authorities cited, see now also <ci:cite searchtype="CASE-REF"><ci:case><ci:caseinfo><ci:decisiondate year="1998"/></ci:caseinfo><ci:caseref ID="cr000070" spanref="cr000070-001" status="unval"><ci:reporter value="NSWConvR"/><ci:page num="55-851"/></ci:caseref><ci:caseref ID="cr000071" spanref="cr000071-002"><ci:reporter value="urj"/><ci:refnum num="BC9800722"/></ci:caseref></ci:case><ci:content><citefragment searchtype="CASE-NAME-REF"><emph typestyle="it">Buzera Pty Ltd v Mezan Enterprises Pty Ltd</emph></citefragment><citefragment searchtype="CASE-CITE-REF"> <ci:span spanid="cr000070-001" status="unval">(1998) NSW ConvR ¶55-851</ci:span>; <ci:span spanid="cr000071-002"> BC9800722</ci:span></citefragment></ci:content></ci:cite>.</text></p></glp:note></case:judgmentbody></case:judgment>
<footnotegrp><footnote fnrtokens="SMN.PRACDEC.190180.FTN1-R" fntoken="SMN.PRACDEC.190180.FTN1" type="default"><fnlabel>1</fnlabel><fnbody>
<p><refpt id="SMN.PRACDEC.190180.FTN1" type="ext"/>
<text><ci:cite searchtype="CASE-REF"><ci:case><ci:caseref ID="cr000061" spanref="cr000061-001" status="unval"><ci:reporter value="SASR"/><ci:edition><ci:date year="1929"/></ci:edition><ci:page num="274"/></ci:caseref></ci:case><ci:content><citefragment searchtype="CASE-NAME-REF"><emph typestyle="it">Moore v Dimond</emph></citefragment><citefragment searchtype="CASE-CITE-REF"> <ci:span spanid="cr000061-001" status="unval">[1929] SASR 274</ci:span></citefragment> <remotelink dpsi="0018" refpt="116739" remotekey1="REFPTID" service="DOC-ID"><inlineobject alttext="Click for CaseBase entry" attachment="web-server" filename="cbcc.gif" type="image"/></remotelink></ci:content></ci:cite>.</text></p></fnbody></footnote>
<footnote fnrtokens="SMN.PRACDEC.190180.FTN2-R" fntoken="SMN.PRACDEC.190180.FTN2" type="default"><fnlabel>2</fnlabel><fnbody>
<p><refpt id="SMN.PRACDEC.190180.FTN2" type="ext"/>
<text><ci:cite searchtype="CASE-REF"><ci:case><ci:caseinfo><ci:decisiondate year="1909"/></ci:caseinfo><ci:caseref ID="cr000062" spanref="cr000062-001" status="unval"><ci:reporter value="SALR"/><ci:page num="28"/></ci:caseref></ci:case><ci:content><citefragment searchtype="CASE-NAME-REF"><emph typestyle="it">Douglas v Hill</emph></citefragment><citefragment searchtype="CASE-CITE-REF"> <ci:span spanid="cr000062-001" status="unval">(1909) SALR 28</ci:span></citefragment></ci:content></ci:cite>.</text></p></fnbody></footnote>
<footnote fnrtokens="SMN.PRACDEC.190180.FTN3-R" fntoken="SMN.PRACDEC.190180.FTN3" type="default"><fnlabel>3</fnlabel><fnbody>
<p><refpt id="SMN.PRACDEC.190180.FTN3" type="ext"/>
<text><ci:cite searchtype="CASE-REF"><ci:content><citefragment searchtype="CASE-NAME-REF"><emph typestyle="it">Moore v Dimond</emph>
</citefragment></ci:content></ci:cite>, above.</text></p></fnbody></footnote>
<footnote fnrtokens="SMN.PRACDEC.190180.FTN4-R" fntoken="SMN.PRACDEC.190180.FTN4" type="default"><fnlabel>4</fnlabel><fnbody>
<p><refpt id="SMN.PRACDEC.190180.FTN4" type="ext"/>
<text><ci:cite searchtype="CASE-REF"><ci:content><citefragment searchtype="CASE-NAME-REF"><emph typestyle="it">Moore v Dimond</emph>
</citefragment></ci:content></ci:cite>, above.</text></p></fnbody></footnote>
<footnote fnrtokens="SMN.PRACDEC.190180.FTN5-R" fntoken="SMN.PRACDEC.190180.FTN5" type="default"><fnlabel>5</fnlabel><fnbody>
<p><refpt id="SMN.PRACDEC.190180.FTN5" type="ext"/>
<text><ci:cite searchtype="CASE-REF"><ci:content><citefragment searchtype="CASE-NAME-REF"><emph typestyle="it">Douglas v Hill</emph>
</citefragment></ci:content></ci:cite>, above.</text></p></fnbody></footnote>
<footnote fnrtokens="SMN.PRACDEC.190180.FTN6-R" fntoken="SMN.PRACDEC.190180.FTN6" type="default"><fnlabel>6</fnlabel><fnbody>
<p><refpt id="SMN.PRACDEC.190180.FTN6" type="ext"/>
<text><ci:cite searchtype="CASE-REF"><ci:case><ci:caseref ID="cr000065" spanref="cr000065-001" status="unval"><ci:reporter value="QB"/><ci:volume num="2"/><ci:edition><ci:date year="1892"/></ci:edition><ci:page num="255"/></ci:caseref></ci:case><ci:content><citefragment searchtype="CASE-NAME-REF"><emph typestyle="it">Foster v Reeves</emph></citefragment><citefragment searchtype="CASE-CITE-REF"> <ci:span spanid="cr000065-001" status="unval">[1892] 2 QB 255</ci:span></citefragment> <remotelink dpsi="0018" refpt="4390" remotekey1="REFPTID" service="DOC-ID"><inlineobject alttext="Click for CaseBase entry" attachment="web-server" filename="cbcc.gif" type="image"/></remotelink></ci:content></ci:cite>.</text></p></fnbody></footnote>
<footnote fnrtokens="SMN.PRACDEC.190180.FTN7-R" fntoken="SMN.PRACDEC.190180.FTN7" type="default"><fnlabel>7</fnlabel><fnbody>
<p><refpt id="SMN.PRACDEC.190180.FTN7" type="ext"/>
<text><ci:cite searchtype="CASE-REF"><ci:content><citefragment searchtype="CASE-NAME-REF"><emph typestyle="it">Foster v Reeves</emph>
</citefragment></ci:content></ci:cite>, above.</text></p></fnbody></footnote>
<footnote fnrtokens="SMN.PRACDEC.190180.FTN8-R" fntoken="SMN.PRACDEC.190180.FTN8" type="default"><fnlabel>8</fnlabel><fnbody>
<p><refpt id="SMN.PRACDEC.190180.FTN8" type="ext"/>
<text><ci:cite searchtype="CASE-REF"><ci:case><ci:caseinfo><ci:decisiondate year="1885"/></ci:caseinfo><ci:caseref ID="cr000066" spanref="cr000066-001" status="unval"><ci:reporter value="SALR"/><ci:volume num="19"/><ci:page num="69"/></ci:caseref></ci:case><ci:content><citefragment searchtype="CASE-NAME-REF"><emph typestyle="it">Shaw v Baker</emph></citefragment><citefragment searchtype="CASE-CITE-REF"> <ci:span spanid="cr000066-001" status="unval">(1885) 19 SALR 69</ci:span></citefragment> <remotelink dpsi="0018" refpt="115522" remotekey1="REFPTID" service="DOC-ID"><inlineobject alttext="Click for CaseBase entry" attachment="web-server" filename="cbcc.gif" type="image"/></remotelink></ci:content></ci:cite>.</text></p></fnbody></footnote>
<footnote fnrtokens="SMN.PRACDEC.190180.FTN9-R" fntoken="SMN.PRACDEC.190180.FTN9" type="default"><fnlabel>9</fnlabel><fnbody>
<p><refpt id="SMN.PRACDEC.190180.FTN9" type="ext"/>
<text><ci:cite searchtype="CASE-REF"><ci:content><citefragment searchtype="CASE-NAME-REF"><emph typestyle="it">Foster v Reeves</emph>
</citefragment></ci:content></ci:cite>, above.</text></p></fnbody></footnote>
<footnote fnrtokens="SMN.PRACDEC.190180.FTN10-R" fntoken="SMN.PRACDEC.190180.FTN10" type="default"><fnlabel>10</fnlabel><fnbody>
<p><refpt id="SMN.PRACDEC.190180.FTN10" type="ext"/>
<text><ci:cite searchtype="CASE-REF"><ci:content><citefragment searchtype="CASE-NAME-REF"><emph typestyle="it">Douglas v Hill</emph>
</citefragment></ci:content></ci:cite>, above.</text></p></fnbody></footnote></footnotegrp>
</case:judgments>
</case:content>
</case:body></CASEDOC>