<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!DOCTYPE CASEDOC PUBLIC "-//LEXISNEXIS//DTD GLP Casedoc v005//EN" "casedoc-norm.dtd">
<CASEDOC type="practicenote" xmlns:case="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/case" xmlns:ci="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/ci" xmlns:comm="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/comm" xmlns:cttr="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/cttr" xmlns:dict="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/dict" xmlns:dig="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/dig" xmlns:docinfo="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/docinfo" xmlns:frm="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/frm" xmlns:glp="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp" xmlns:in="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/in" xmlns:jrnl="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/jrnl" xmlns:leg="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/leg" xmlns:lnci="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnci" xmlns:lncle="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lncle" xmlns:lnclx="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnclx" xmlns:lndel="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lndel" xmlns:lndocmeta="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lndocmeta" xmlns:lngntxt="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lngntxt" xmlns:lnlit="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnlit" xmlns:lnv="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnv" xmlns:lnvni="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnvni" xmlns:lnvx="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnvx" xmlns:lnvxe="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnvxe" xmlns:nitf="urn:nitf:iptc.org.20010418.NITF" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3c.org/1999/xhtml">
<docinfo partitionnum="3"><docinfo:dpsi id-string="05CC"/><docinfo:doc-heading>[DC (Civil) 6] Practice Note DC (Civil) 6 Defamation</docinfo:doc-heading><docinfo:doc-id>UCPN_PRACNOTE.SGM_UCPN.PN.DC6</docinfo:doc-id><docinfo:doc-lang lang="en"/><docinfo:doc-country iso-cc="AU"/><docinfo:hier><docinfo:hierlev role="ancestor"><heading><title>PRACTICE NOTES</title></heading><docinfo:hierlev role="ancestor"><heading><title>District Court Practice Notes</title></heading><docinfo:hierlev role="me"><heading><edpnum>[DC (Civil) 6]</edpnum><desig><designum>Practice Note DC (Civil) 6</designum></desig><title>Defamation</title></heading></docinfo:hierlev></docinfo:hierlev></docinfo:hierlev></docinfo:hier><docinfo:bookseqnum>130470000</docinfo:bookseqnum><docinfo:lbu-meta><docinfo:metaitem name="lbu-sourcename" value="Ritchie's Uniform Civil Procedure NSW"/><docinfo:metaitem name="parent-docid" value="UCPN.PRACNOTE"/><docinfo:metaitem name="parent-filename" value="pracnote.xml"/><docinfo:metaitem name="parent-docid" value="UCPN_PRACNOTE.SGM_UCPN.PN.DC6"/><docinfo:metaitem name="parent-filename" value="pracnote1094.xml"/></docinfo:lbu-meta><docinfo:selector>case</docinfo:selector><docinfo:load-date><date day="10" month="11" year="2011">10 November 2011</date></docinfo:load-date></docinfo>
<case:body><heading searchtype="PRACTICE-NOTE"><edpnum><refpt id="UCPN.PN.DC6" type="ext"/>[DC (Civil) 6]</edpnum>
<desig><designum>Practice Note DC (Civil) 6</designum></desig></heading>
<case:headnote>
<case:info><case:casename searchtype="PRACTICE-NOTE">Defamation</case:casename></case:info></case:headnote><case:content>
<case:judgments><case:judgment><case:judgmentbody>
<p>
<text>1. All actions for defamation, injurious falsehood or related claims of injury to reputation commenced in the Sydney Registry of the Court should be entered in the Defamation List irrespective of anticipated length of trial. Actions commenced in registries other than the Sydney registry will be case managed from Sydney (by telephone attendance if necessary) until pleadings are closed.</text></p>
<p>
<text>2. All actions entered into the Defamation List will be managed from the moment of such entry by a Judge having the control of the List.</text></p>
<p>
<text>3. Actions may be entered in the Defamation List by:</text></p>
<p>
<text>3.1 The Plaintiff endorsing the statement of claim, or the defendant endorsing the notice of grounds of defence &#x2018;<emph typestyle="bf">DEFAMATION LIST</emph>&#x2019; next under the heading and title on the statement of claim or the notice of grounds of defence, as the case may require.</text></p>
<p>
<text>3.2 The filing of a consent order, after the filing of the notice of grounds of defence, for entry of the action into the Defamation List.</text></p>
<p>
<text>3.3 Order of the Court on a notice of motion filed by the plaintiff, or a defendant who has filed a notice of grounds of defence, for entry of the action into the Defamation List, at any time after a notice of grounds of defence has been filed.</text></p>
<p>
<text>3.4 Order of the Court on its own motion.</text></p>
<p>
<text>4. Upon an action being entered in the Defamation List, the Registry will allocate a date in the next available <emph typestyle="bf">Defamation List Directions List</emph> for directions before a Judge controlling the List. Directions will then be given as to the preparation of the proceedings for determination and the method of such determination including the hearing of any part of the trial by a jury.</text></p>
<p>
<text>5. The Judge controlling the list may, from time to time, issue standard directions in relation to the conduct of matters in the list including, but not limited to, requirements for the provision of outlines of argument in relation to interlocutory applications and matters such as service of pleadings and the time for completing of interlocutory proceedings.</text></p>
<p>
<text>6. Defamation, injurious falsehood and related claims of injury to reputation will continue to be case managed in accordance with Part 49 of the District Court Rules until further notice.</text></p>
<p>
<text>The following should be particularly noted:</text></p>
<p>
<text>6.1 Where there is a separate trial because a defendant has not consented to trial without a jury, a plaintiff may request that any additional hearing fee should be paid by the defendant rather than the plaintiff. However, any such application must be made in a timely manner.</text></p>
<p>
<text>6.2 The practice of application for orders and for arguments concerning pleadings will continue to be by way of letters inter partes and to the court and notices of motion need not be filed unless the court so orders.</text></p>
<p>
<text>7. It is anticipated that defamation actions will be subject to the Uniform Procedure Act and Rules when amendments to the Defamation Act 1974 (NSW) are passed in early 2006.</text></p></case:judgmentbody></case:judgment></case:judgments>
<case:appendix><sigblock>
<p><text><person><name.text>The Hon Justice RO Blanch AM</name.text>
<role>Chief Judge</role></person>
<date>9 August 2005</date></text></p></sigblock>
</case:appendix>
</case:content>
</case:body></CASEDOC>