<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!DOCTYPE CASEDOC PUBLIC "-//LEXISNEXIS//DTD GLP Casedoc v005//EN" "casedoc-norm.dtd">
<CASEDOC type="fulltext" xmlns:case="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/case" xmlns:ci="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/ci" xmlns:comm="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/comm" xmlns:cttr="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/cttr" xmlns:dict="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/dict" xmlns:dig="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/dig" xmlns:docinfo="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/docinfo" xmlns:frm="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/frm" xmlns:glp="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp" xmlns:in="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/in" xmlns:jrnl="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/jrnl" xmlns:leg="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/leg" xmlns:lnci="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnci" xmlns:lncle="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lncle" xmlns:lnclx="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnclx" xmlns:lndel="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lndel" xmlns:lndocmeta="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lndocmeta" xmlns:lngntxt="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lngntxt" xmlns:lnlit="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnlit" xmlns:lnv="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnv" xmlns:lnvni="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnvni" xmlns:lnvx="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnvx" xmlns:lnvxe="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnvxe" xmlns:nitf="urn:nitf:iptc.org.20010418.NITF" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3c.org/1999/xhtml">
<docinfo partitionnum="3"><docinfo:dpsi id-string="05CC"/><docinfo:doc-heading>[456,195] SOLOMON v DESIGN RESOURCE INTERNATIONAL PTY LTD*</docinfo:doc-heading><docinfo:doc-id>UCPN_PRACDEC.SGM_UCPN.PRACDEC.456195</docinfo:doc-id><docinfo:doc-lang lang="en"/><docinfo:doc-country iso-cc="AU"/><docinfo:hier><docinfo:hierlev role="ancestor"><heading><title>PRACTICE DECISIONS</title></heading><docinfo:hierlev role="ancestor"><heading><title>PRACTICE DECISIONS</title></heading><docinfo:hierlev role="me"><heading><edpnum>[456,195]</edpnum><title>SOLOMON v DESIGN RESOURCE INTERNATIONAL PTY LTD*</title></heading></docinfo:hierlev></docinfo:hierlev></docinfo:hierlev></docinfo:hier><docinfo:bookseqnum>160140000</docinfo:bookseqnum><docinfo:lbu-meta><docinfo:metaitem name="lbu-sourcename" value="Ritchie's Uniform Civil Procedure NSW"/><docinfo:metaitem name="parent-docid" value="UCPN.PRACDEC"/><docinfo:metaitem name="parent-filename" value="pracdec.xml"/><docinfo:metaitem name="parent-docid" value="UCPN_PRACDEC.SGM_UCPN.PRACDEC.456195"/><docinfo:metaitem name="parent-filename" value="pracdec1028.xml"/></docinfo:lbu-meta><docinfo:selector>case</docinfo:selector><docinfo:load-date><date day="11" month="09" year="2012">11 September 2012</date></docinfo:load-date></docinfo>
<case:body><heading searchtype="PRACTICE-NOTE"><edpnum><refpt id="UCPN.PRACDEC.456195" type="ext"/>[456,195]</edpnum></heading>
<case:headnote>
<case:info><case:casename searchtype="PRACTICE-NOTE">SOLOMON v DESIGN RESOURCE INTERNATIONAL PTY LTD*</case:casename></case:info>
<case:info>
<case:courtinfo><case:courtname>Local Court of New South Wales, Sydney</case:courtname>
<case:judges><case:judge>Lawson M</case:judge>
</case:judges><case:dates><case:decisiondate>10 May 1991</case:decisiondate></case:dates>
<case:filenum>No 7855/89</case:filenum>
</case:courtinfo></case:info><catchwordgrp><catchwords><catchphrase>CPA ss 40 and 42 &#x2014; [former LC(CC)R Pt 38 r 10]</catchphrase><catchphrase>Arbitration award</catchphrase><catchphrase>Application for rehearing</catchphrase><catchphrase>No date endorsed on copy of award forwarded to parties under Pt 38 r 10</catchphrase><catchphrase>Period prescribed for the purposes of s 21H(5) of the Local Courts (Civil Claims) Act 1970 never commences to run</catchphrase><catchphrase>No deemed judgment based on the award comes into existence.</catchphrase></catchwords>
</catchwordgrp></case:headnote><case:content>
<case:judgments><case:judgment><case:courtinfo><case:judges><case:judge>Lawson M</case:judge></case:judges></case:courtinfo>
<case:judgmentbody>
<p>
<text>The plaintiff has made application for an order extending the time for filing an application for rehearing of a matter determined at arbitration. It was not in dispute that generally speaking such an order can properly be made on the basis examined in <ci:cite searchtype="CASE-REF"><ci:case><ci:caseinfo><ci:decisiondate year="1988"/></ci:caseinfo><ci:caseref ID="cr000114" spanref="cr000114-001"><ci:reporter value="NSWLR"/><ci:volume num="15"/><ci:page num="303"/></ci:caseref></ci:case><ci:content><citefragment searchtype="CASE-NAME-REF"><emph typestyle="it">El Ali v GIO (NSW)</emph></citefragment><citefragment searchtype="CASE-CITE-REF"> <ci:span spanid="cr000114-001">(1988) 15 NSWLR 303</ci:span></citefragment> <remotelink dpsi="0018" refpt="15742" remotekey1="REFPTID" service="DOC-ID"><inlineobject alttext="Click for CaseBase entry" attachment="web-server" filename="cbcc.gif" type="image"/></remotelink></ci:content></ci:cite>. The basis of the present application appeared from the affidavits of the plaintiff and the plaintiff's solicitor, Mr Hughes, and was not in dispute once certain ambiguities concerning paras 2 and 5 of Mr Hughes' affidavit had been clarified. That basis was in essence that the plaintiff, not having attended the arbitration hearing or been represented there, received notice of the making of an award on which no endorsement appeared as to the date of its sending as required by Pt 38 r 10(6) of the Local Court (Civil Claims) Rules. Thereafter based on certain assumptions which proved unfounded as to the time available for requesting a rehearing, the plaintiff made application after the period had expired so that the application was incompetent.</text></p>
<p>
<text>The application before me seemed to raise a preliminary question of some significance to which the parties had not adverted. An application for rehearing must be made before the relevant award becomes enforceable as a judgment of the court: Arbitration (Civil Actions) Act 1983 s 18(2). An award made under that Act is to be deemed to be a judgment or order of the court after the expiration of the time prescribed by the Rules: Local Courts (Civil Claims) Act s 21H(5).</text></p>
<p>
<text>Part 38 r 11 prescribes this time for relevant purposes as the period of 28 days immediately following the date required to be endorsed by the registrar on the copy of the award, and the registrar's notice required to be sent to the parties or their representatives under Pt 38 r 10(6).</text></p>
<p>
<text>On the undisputed evidence in the present case no date was so endorsed on the copy of the award sent to the plaintiff. In my view it follows from that omission that the period prescribed for the purposes of s 21H(5) has never commenced, and that no order is necessary to enable the plaintiff to make a competent application for rehearing. I have formed certain views myself about whether such an application if made should be granted, having regard to s 18(2A) of the Arbitration (Civil Actions) Act, but since the ordinary practice is for the registrar to exercise the relevant discretion in the first instance I will not express those views. I should perhaps add that it would follow from the views I have expressed that no deemed judgment based on the award is in existence. The deeming provision of s 21H(5) is based on the expiration of a prescribed period. If the period did not commence it cannot have expired. It would seem appropriate in the circumstances for application to be made to the registrar to comply with Pt 38 r 10.</text></p>
<p>
<text>His Worship then considered the question of costs.</text></p></case:judgmentbody></case:judgment>
</case:judgments>
</case:content>
</case:body></CASEDOC>