<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!DOCTYPE CASEDOC PUBLIC "-//LEXISNEXIS//DTD GLP Casedoc v005//EN" "casedoc-norm.dtd">
<CASEDOC type="fulltext" xmlns:case="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/case" xmlns:ci="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/ci" xmlns:comm="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/comm" xmlns:cttr="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/cttr" xmlns:dict="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/dict" xmlns:dig="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/dig" xmlns:docinfo="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/docinfo" xmlns:frm="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/frm" xmlns:glp="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp" xmlns:in="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/in" xmlns:jrnl="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/jrnl" xmlns:leg="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/leg" xmlns:lnci="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnci" xmlns:lncle="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lncle" xmlns:lnclx="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnclx" xmlns:lndel="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lndel" xmlns:lndocmeta="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lndocmeta" xmlns:lngntxt="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lngntxt" xmlns:lnlit="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnlit" xmlns:lnv="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnv" xmlns:lnvni="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnvni" xmlns:lnvx="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnvx" xmlns:lnvxe="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnvxe" xmlns:nitf="urn:nitf:iptc.org.20010418.NITF" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3c.org/1999/xhtml">
<docinfo partitionnum="3"><docinfo:dpsi id-string="05CC"/><docinfo:doc-heading>[456,155] LEYMAR CONSTRUCTIONS PTY LTD AND THE COMPANIES ACT</docinfo:doc-heading><docinfo:doc-id>UCPN_PRACDEC.SGM_UCPN.PRACDEC.456155</docinfo:doc-id><docinfo:doc-lang lang="en"/><docinfo:doc-country iso-cc="AU"/><docinfo:hier><docinfo:hierlev role="ancestor"><heading><title>PRACTICE DECISIONS</title></heading><docinfo:hierlev role="ancestor"><heading><title>PRACTICE DECISIONS</title></heading><docinfo:hierlev role="me"><heading><edpnum>[456,155]</edpnum><title>LEYMAR CONSTRUCTIONS PTY LTD AND THE COMPANIES ACT</title></heading></docinfo:hierlev></docinfo:hierlev></docinfo:hierlev></docinfo:hier><docinfo:bookseqnum>160100000</docinfo:bookseqnum><docinfo:lbu-meta><docinfo:metaitem name="lbu-sourcename" value="Ritchie's Uniform Civil Procedure NSW"/><docinfo:metaitem name="parent-docid" value="UCPN.PRACDEC"/><docinfo:metaitem name="parent-filename" value="pracdec.xml"/><docinfo:metaitem name="parent-docid" value="UCPN_PRACDEC.SGM_UCPN.PRACDEC.456155"/><docinfo:metaitem name="parent-filename" value="pracdec1020.xml"/></docinfo:lbu-meta><docinfo:selector>case</docinfo:selector><docinfo:load-date><date day="11" month="09" year="2012">11 September 2012</date></docinfo:load-date></docinfo>
<case:body><heading searchtype="PRACTICE-NOTE"><edpnum><refpt id="UCPN.PRACDEC.456155" type="ext"/>[456,155]</edpnum></heading>
<case:headnote>
<case:info><case:casename searchtype="PRACTICE-NOTE">LEYMAR CONSTRUCTIONS PTY LTD AND THE COMPANIES ACT</case:casename></case:info>
<case:info>
<case:courtinfo><case:courtname>Supreme Court NSW</case:courtname>
<case:judges><case:judge>Needham J</case:judge>
</case:judges><case:dates><case:decisiondate>27 October 1980</case:decisiondate></case:dates>
<case:filenum>ED No 2987/76</case:filenum>
</case:courtinfo></case:info><catchwordgrp><catchwords><catchphrase>UCPR r 17.7 &#x2014; [SCR Pt 18 r 3]</catchphrase><catchphrase>Ability of the court to give judgment for part of a claim on admissions without prejudice to the plaintiff pursuing the balance of the claim</catchphrase></catchwords>
</catchwordgrp></case:headnote><case:content>
<case:judgments><case:judgment><case:courtinfo><case:judges><case:judge>Needham J</case:judge></case:judges></case:courtinfo>
<case:judgmentbody>
<p>
<text>This is an application under Pt 18 r 3 of the Rules of the Supreme Court, under which the court is empowered to direct the entry of any judgment or make any order to which the applicant is entitled where admissions have been made by another party, whether by the pleading or otherwise. Subrule (2) provides that the Court may exercise its powers under subr (1), notwithstanding that other questions in the proceedings have not been determined.</text></p>
<p>
<text>The application is made by the liquidator of the company, who was appointed liquidator in June 1978 to take the place of the original liquidator, Mr Belfer, who applied for leave to resign his appointment under a voluntary winding-up. The company was wound up voluntarily on 3 March 1976, but prior to that time proceedings had been brought against the company by a firm of architects, who are suing the company for a sum of approximately $20,000. The original liquidator sold certain property belonging to the company and, from the proceeds of that sale, $90,624 was paid to the respondents to these proceedings, Mr and Mrs Braham.</text></p>
<p>
<text>On 11 May 1977 the present Chief Judge in Equity directed the liquidator to commence proceedings against the Brahams for the recovery of the amount and the summons was issued on 24 May 1977.</text></p>
<p>
<text>On 22nd June 1977 Mr I D Ferrier sent a letter to the respondents' solicitors calculating, according to the books of the company and according, no doubt, to his instructions, the amount which, on an account between the respondents, who were directors of the company, and the company, was owing by the respondents to the company. Mr Ferrier's calculation showed that the sum of $6,277.37 was owing by the respondents to the company as a result of the account which he took.</text></p>
<p>
<text>On 6 July the respondents filed points of defence in the proceedings, by para 3 of which they appear to concede a liability of $90,624, although there was a denial of that indebtedness in para 1, but the concession in para 3 is coupled with a claim that there is a set off against that sum of $84,347.48.</text></p>
<p>
<text>In an affidavit sworn on the same day as the points of defence were filed, Mr Braham, in para 5, referred to the annexed letter from Mr Ferrier and said:</text>
<blockquote>
<p>
<text>Mr Ferrier, subject to the matters set forth in his letter, shows at p 4 that the amended liability for purpose of reconciliation of myself to the company is $6,277.37. I accept Mr Ferrier's calculations and I am ready, willing and able to pay this money to the liquidator forthwith.</text></p></blockquote></p>
<p>
<text>What transpired thereafter is not the subject of evidence, but it appears that that sum was not paid to the liquidator and, presumably, no request was made by the liquidator for that payment.</text></p>
<p>
<text>Immediately prior to the swearing of that affidavit, in June 1977 two separate sums of $500 had been paid to the liquidator, so the evidence indicates, for the purpose of the proceedings brought by the architects against the company and the company's cross-claim against the architects. That sum, it appears, was returned to the payer, which I presume was Mr Braham, and, later on, in March 1978, was paid into court. Prior to that payment in, the respondents paid into court on 9 February 1978 the sum of $4,277.37.</text></p>
<p>
<text>The liquidator made application for directions, and on 20 March 1978 Powell J directed the liquidator that, on the evidence before him at that time, he was not justified in accepting the money paid into court in full satisfaction of the claim.</text></p>
<p>
<text>The liquidator has approximately $1,000 in the liquidation bank account and he says that he requires the $6,277.37 to enable him to take legal advice on three matters, namely, the question whether he is likely to succeed in the proceedings against the Brahams for the sum of $90,624.85 or some other sum; secondly, the question whether the architects have a good claim against the company; and, thirdly, the question whether the company has a good claim against the architects. He says that he cannot proceed with the litigation, either against the architects or against the Brahams unless he obtains funds and the amount which he seeks judgment for in this application would assist him to continue with that litigation if he were advised to so.</text></p>
<p>
<text>The Brahams have offered an indemnity to the liquidator in respect of the proceedings against the architects and, although these proceedings were commenced, apparently, at the instigation of the architect, there is no suggestion that the liquidator has any indemnity in respect of the proceedings against Mr and Mrs Braham. The situation appears to be that each of the architects and the Brahams desires the liquidator to proceed against the other.</text></p>
<p>
<text>It is submitted on behalf of the liquidator that the claim made in the summons, that is, that judgment be entered for the sum of $6,277.37 with interest at ten per cent per annum from 3 March 1976 and for an order that the entry of judgment for the said sum should not prejudice the right of the liquidator to claim the balance of the sum of $90,624.85 should be made in accordance with the provisions of Pt 18 r 3.</text></p>
<p>
<text>I was referred to the decision of the English Court of Appeal in <ci:cite searchtype="CASE-REF"><ci:case><ci:caseref ID="cr000081" spanref="cr000081-001"><ci:reporter value="All ER"/><ci:volume num="2"/><ci:edition><ci:date year="1950"/></ci:edition><ci:page num="1096"/></ci:caseref></ci:case><ci:content><citefragment searchtype="CASE-NAME-REF"><emph typestyle="it">Lancashire Welders Ltd v Harland &amp; Wolff Ltd</emph></citefragment><citefragment searchtype="CASE-CITE-REF"> <ci:span spanid="cr000081-001">[1950] 2 All ER 1096</ci:span></citefragment></ci:content></ci:cite>. In that case there had been an admission of an amount of approximately £1,700 in respect of a claim of £31,000 and the £1,700-odd was paid into court in full satisfaction of the plaintiff's claim. The Court of Appeal overruled the decision of the single judge, who had upheld an order of the District Registrar refusing the application for judgment in the lower sum without prejudice to the pursuit of the larger sum against the defendants in the case.</text></p>
<p>
<text>It is a not dissimilar case to the present, although it is submitted that it is distinguishable on a number of grounds: first of all, that the amount admitted in this case was an amount reached by calculation of an original amount due and amounts which are able to be setoff from that original amount. It was not, it was suggested, a case where the plaintiffs were pursuing amounts due under a number of different transactions and the defendants were admitting some transactions and denying others. Undoubtedly, that is the case here, and if it were the case that the sum arrived at by Mr Ferrier was in some way unjust to the claims of Mr and Mrs Braham as against the company, it would be a good ground, I think, for declining to make the order. However, there is no suggestion in the evidence in this case, so far as I am aware, that it could possibly be found that the Brahams would owe less than the amount they admit in the points of defence and in Mr Braham's affidavit. That being so, it does not seem to me that the distinction sought to be made is a valid one.</text></p>
<p>
<text>It is then suggested that the offer of indemnity by the Brahams to pursue the claim against the architects is a matter which should result in the refusal of this order which is sought. However as I have said, the liquidator does not seek to have the money paid to him purely to pursue the architects. His intention is to obtain advice on whether he can pursue the Brahams as well.</text></p>
<p>
<text>Further, it is said that the fact that the amount has been paid into court &#x2014; and I would interpolate that the payment into court was well after the admission made by the respondents &#x2014; necessitated the refusal of the application because, it was said, if a plaintiff can get an order in the amount of an amount paid into court, the provisions of the rules relating to payment into court and payment out to plaintiffs would be circumvented and the defendant would not get the benefit of having paid the sum into court.</text></p>
<p>
<text>If the only evidence upon which the liquidator could rely was a payment into court, I think there is considerable substance in the submission. It would, I agree, be a strange result if a defendant, having paid money into court under Pt 22 of the Rules, could find himself a respondent to an application for judgment in respect of the amount paid into court without prejudice to the balance of the claim of the plaintiff. But, in this case, the evidence is not limited to that aspect at all. As I have pointed out, the admission was made long before the amount was paid into court and it is open to the liquidator to say that he should not be denied the benefit of that admission merely by the fact that the defendants to the proceedings have paid the amount admitted into court. The admission still exists and, if an order were made under Pt 18 r 3, no doubt, the correct form of order would be to give leave to the plaintiff to enter judgment for the sum without prejudice to the continuation of the proceedings but to give leave to the defendants to withdraw the amount paid into court.</text></p>
<p>
<text>An order under Pt 18 r 3 is discretionary, but it seems to me in this case that the discretionary considerations are all one way. The respondent defendants cannot, it seems to me, suffer in any way from the making of the order, because if the plaintiff proceeds with his claim and is unable to prove any further debt then the defendants, in the principal proceedings, will be entitled to judgment and an order for their costs. On the other hand, the liquidator is plainly hampered in the administration of the company's affairs and the making of the order would assist greatly in the resolution of two substantial pieces of litigation in the Court. If the order were not made, it seems to me that the liquidator would be forced to abandon the proceedings against the Brahams unless, pursuant to the proposed indemnity, he were to be successful in the proceedings against the architects. In the circumstances, I do not think that that is a desirable situation to exist, where it is possible within the rules and on a proper discretionary approach to the rules to ensure that the liquidator would be enabled to proceed with the administration of the company's affairs.</text></p>
<p>
<text>When I referred to the two amounts of $500 having been paid to the liquidator in June and having been refunded to the Brahams, I was apparently in error. A further sum of $1,000 had been paid to the liquidator in November 1977 and that was the sum which was refunded to the Brahams, and, subsequently, paid into Court on 3 March 1978.</text></p>
<p>
<text>I will indicate that I will make the orders, without any order for interest at this stage, either for $6,277.37 or, if the $1,000 has already been paid for that sum less $1,000.</text></p>
<p>
<text>(Stood down for short minutes.)</text></p></case:judgmentbody></case:judgment>
</case:judgments>
</case:content>
</case:body></CASEDOC>