<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!DOCTYPE CASEDOC PUBLIC "-//LEXISNEXIS//DTD GLP Casedoc v005//EN" "casedoc-norm.dtd">
<CASEDOC type="fulltext" xmlns:case="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/case" xmlns:ci="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/ci" xmlns:comm="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/comm" xmlns:cttr="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/cttr" xmlns:dict="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/dict" xmlns:dig="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/dig" xmlns:docinfo="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/docinfo" xmlns:frm="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/frm" xmlns:glp="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp" xmlns:in="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/in" xmlns:jrnl="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/jrnl" xmlns:leg="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/leg" xmlns:lnci="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnci" xmlns:lncle="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lncle" xmlns:lnclx="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnclx" xmlns:lndel="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lndel" xmlns:lndocmeta="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lndocmeta" xmlns:lngntxt="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lngntxt" xmlns:lnlit="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnlit" xmlns:lnv="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnv" xmlns:lnvni="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnvni" xmlns:lnvx="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnvx" xmlns:lnvxe="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnvxe" xmlns:nitf="urn:nitf:iptc.org.20010418.NITF" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3c.org/1999/xhtml">
<docinfo partitionnum="3"><docinfo:dpsi id-string="05CC"/><docinfo:doc-heading>[456,135] FULLERTON v GARDINER</docinfo:doc-heading><docinfo:doc-id>UCPN_PRACDEC.SGM_UCPN.PRACDEC.456135</docinfo:doc-id><docinfo:doc-lang lang="en"/><docinfo:doc-country iso-cc="AU"/><docinfo:hier><docinfo:hierlev role="ancestor"><heading><title>PRACTICE DECISIONS</title></heading><docinfo:hierlev role="ancestor"><heading><title>PRACTICE DECISIONS</title></heading><docinfo:hierlev role="me"><heading><edpnum>[456,135]</edpnum><title>FULLERTON v GARDINER</title></heading></docinfo:hierlev></docinfo:hierlev></docinfo:hierlev></docinfo:hier><docinfo:bookseqnum>160060000</docinfo:bookseqnum><docinfo:lbu-meta><docinfo:metaitem name="lbu-sourcename" value="Ritchie's Uniform Civil Procedure NSW"/><docinfo:metaitem name="parent-docid" value="UCPN.PRACDEC"/><docinfo:metaitem name="parent-filename" value="pracdec.xml"/><docinfo:metaitem name="parent-docid" value="UCPN_PRACDEC.SGM_UCPN.PRACDEC.456135"/><docinfo:metaitem name="parent-filename" value="pracdec1012.xml"/></docinfo:lbu-meta><docinfo:selector>case</docinfo:selector><docinfo:load-date><date day="11" month="09" year="2012">11 September 2012</date></docinfo:load-date></docinfo>
<case:body><heading searchtype="PRACTICE-NOTE"><edpnum><refpt id="UCPN.PRACDEC.456135" type="ext"/>[456,135]</edpnum></heading>
<case:headnote>
<case:info><case:casename searchtype="PRACTICE-NOTE">FULLERTON v GARDINER</case:casename></case:info>
<case:info>
<case:courtinfo><case:courtname>Supreme Court NSW</case:courtname>
<case:judges><case:judge>Powell J</case:judge>
</case:judges><case:dates><case:decisiondate>31 October 1978</case:decisiondate></case:dates>
<case:filenum>ED No 2715/77</case:filenum>
</case:courtinfo></case:info><catchwordgrp><catchwords><catchphrase>SCR Pt 55 r 9</catchphrase><catchphrase>Contempt proceedings</catchphrase><catchphrase>compliance with Rules</catchphrase></catchwords>
</catchwordgrp></case:headnote><case:content>
<case:judgments><case:judgment><case:courtinfo><case:judges><case:judge>Powell J</case:judge></case:judges></case:courtinfo>
<case:judgmentbody>
<p>
<text>[Extract from judgment:] This being so I turn to the grounds upon which Mr J F Linton, who appeared for the plaintiff, submitted that no orders should be made on the notice of motion.</text></p>
<p>
<text>First, the question of procedural irregularity. The irregularities upon which Mr Linton relies are, firstly, that no minute of the orders, duly endorsed was, as required by rr 8(1) and 8(3) of Pt 42 of the Rules, served upon the plaintiff prior to the commencement of the present proceedings and, secondly, that the defendant's affidavit of 19 October 1978, was not served on the plaintiff personally as required, so Mr Linton submitted, by r 9 of Pt 55 of the Rules.</text></p>
<p>
<text>It is true that some of the cases dealing with attachment of parties for a contempt in procedure have described the procedure or attachment as one said <emph typestyle="it">strictissimi juris</emph>. Further, it has been stated that upon such applications the Rules must be strictly complied with. However, it seems to me, as indeed it seemed to Else-Mitchell J in <ci:cite searchtype="CASE-REF"><ci:case><ci:caseinfo><ci:decisiondate year="1959"/></ci:caseinfo><ci:caseref ID="cr000048" spanref="cr000048-001" status="unval"><ci:reporter value="WNNSW"/><ci:volume num="76"/><ci:page num="391"/></ci:caseref><ci:caseref anaphref="cr000048" spanref="cr000048-002" status="unval"><ci:pinpoint num="383" targettype="page"/></ci:caseref></ci:case><ci:content><citefragment searchtype="CASE-NAME-REF"><emph typestyle="it">Spindler v Balog</emph></citefragment><citefragment searchtype="CASE-CITE-REF"> <ci:span spanid="cr000048-001" status="unval">(1959) 76 WN (NSW) 391</ci:span> <ci:span spanid="cr000048-002" status="unval">at 383</ci:span></citefragment> <remotelink dpsi="0018" refpt="184097" remotekey1="REFPTID" service="DOC-ID"><inlineobject alttext="Click for CaseBase entry" attachment="web-server" filename="cbcc.gif" type="image"/></remotelink></ci:content></ci:cite>, that such expressions mean no more than that the court must not proceed on less than proper proof of the non-compliance or contempt in procedure nor on a course of procedure other than that prescribed by the Supreme Court Act or the Rules.</text></p>
<p>
<text>While it is true that, as a general rule, where it is sought to enforce by attachment an order of the court there must first have been served upon the party sought to be attached a duly endorsed minute of the order, r 8(6) of Pt 42 of the Rules, which merely reflects what, in my experience, over a quarter of a century, always has been the practice of the court, provides as follows:</text>
<blockquote><legfragment>
<leg:level>
<leg:level-vrnt leveltype="subrul">
<leg:heading inline="true"><desig><designum>(6)</designum></desig></leg:heading>
<leg:levelbody>
<leg:bodytext>
<p><text>Where a person liable to committal or sequestration of his property by way of enforcement of a judgment has notice of the judgment&#x2014;</text></p>
<l>
<li><lilabel>(a)</lilabel>
<p><text>by being present when the judgment is directed to be entered or when the order is made; or</text></p></li>
<li><lilabel>(b)</lilabel>
<p><text>by being notified of the terms of the judgment whether by telephone, telegram or otherwise,</text></p></li>
</l>
<p><text>the judgment may be enforced by committal of that person or by sequestration of his property notwithstanding that service has not been effected in accordance with this rule.</text></p>
</leg:bodytext>
</leg:levelbody>
</leg:level-vrnt>
</leg:level>
</legfragment></blockquote>
</p>
<p>
<text>I appreciate that the discretion to proceed thus vested in this court is one which will normally be exercised sparingly and only if there are good grounds (see <ci:cite searchtype="CASE-REF"><ci:case><ci:caseref ID="cr000049" spanref="cr000049-001"><ci:reporter value="NSWLR"/><ci:volume num="1"/><ci:edition><ci:date year="1974"/></ci:edition><ci:page num="655"/></ci:caseref></ci:case><ci:content><citefragment searchtype="CASE-NAME-REF"><emph typestyle="it">Drummoyne Municipal Council v Lewis</emph></citefragment><citefragment searchtype="CASE-CITE-REF"> <ci:span spanid="cr000049-001">[1974] 1 NSWLR 655</ci:span></citefragment> <remotelink dpsi="0018" refpt="44064" remotekey1="REFPTID" service="DOC-ID"><inlineobject alttext="Click for CaseBase entry" attachment="web-server" filename="cbcc.gif" type="image"/></remotelink></ci:content></ci:cite> per Holland J). This, however, seems to be a case in which the discretion should be exercised, for it is clear that the plaintiff not only knew of, and consented to, the terms of the injunction presently under consideration, but was present in court when the formal orders were made. Further, it is clear, even if I accept his evidence in its entirety, that the plaintiff appreciated, at the very least, that if he assaulted the defendant he would be in breach of the injunction, that he appreciated that any attempt to remove the child from the defendant's care would be wrong, and, finally, that he appreciated that if he acted in defiance to the order of the court he would render himself liable to some form of penalty, which penalty, so he thought, would take the form of a fine or a bond to be of good behaviour.</text></p>
<p>
<text>So far as the second matter is concerned it seems to me that r 9 of Pt 55 of the Rules requires only that the affidavits setting out the events referred to in the statement of charge should be served personally; and, as I have pointed out above no application was made to amend the notice of motion by adding the incident to those particularized in the statement of charge. But even if I be wrong in this view, it is clear that the court has a residual discretion to dispense with compliance of the Rules; in particular, it has a discretion to permit evidence in support of the charges to be given orally at the hearing (see, eg r 8(2) of Pt 55). In the present case it is clear that the plaintiff's solicitors were served with the affidavit in question in sufficient time to enable the plaintiff not only to file an affidavit in reply to the defendant's affidavit but as well to obtain by the issue of the subpoena <emph typestyle="it">ad testificandum</emph> the evidence of the witness who was claimed to support his denial of the incident alleged. To the extent, therefore, to which it may be necessary, I would dispense with compliance of the Rules in this regard.</text></p>
<p>
<text>I turn then to the question of the alleged contempts.</text></p>
<p>
<text>It is necessary first to determine the full extent of the restraint imposed upon the plaintiff by the injunction now in question.</text></p>
<p>
<text>It is, I think, clear that it is far wider in ambit than the plaintiff claims he understands it to be. The word &#x201c;molestation&#x201d; has a long history of use in the context of separation agreements &#x2014; a context not dissimilar from that in the present case. What is comprehended is, in my view, any act, on the part of the plaintiff, he being the one restrained, the natural tendency of which is to injure or annoy, and which is intended to injure or annoy, the defendant. This interpretation, which bears support from the cases dealing with separation agreements, would comprehend not only physical violence offered by the plaintiff to the defendant but, as well, threats of violence, and, on a lesser plane, if such it can be described, the alleged course of watching and besetting the defendant's home.</text></p>
<p>
<text>Mr Linton has submitted that as proceedings for attachment are criminal in nature I must first be satisfied beyond all reasonable doubt of the occurrence of the incidents alleged against the plaintiff before I can find him guilty of contempt.</text></p>
<p>
<text>While it is true that proceedings seeking to punish a person for contempt involving interference with a court of justice or for scandalizing the court are truly criminal in nature; for such contempt is a criminal offence at common law (see <ci:cite searchtype="CASE-REF"><ci:case><ci:caseinfo><ci:decisiondate year="1954"/></ci:caseinfo><ci:caseref ID="cr000050" spanref="cr000050-001" status="unval"><ci:reporter value="CLR"/><ci:volume num="93"/><ci:page num="325"/></ci:caseref></ci:case><ci:content><citefragment searchtype="CASE-NAME-REF"><emph typestyle="it">Consolidated Press Ltd v McRae</emph></citefragment><citefragment searchtype="CASE-CITE-REF"> <ci:span spanid="cr000050-001" status="unval">(1954) 93 CLR 325</ci:span></citefragment></ci:content></ci:cite>; <ci:cite searchtype="CASE-REF"><ci:case><ci:caseref ID="cr000051" spanref="cr000051-001"><ci:reporter value="NSWLR"/><ci:volume num="2"/><ci:edition><ci:date year="1972"/></ci:edition><ci:page num="887"/></ci:caseref></ci:case><ci:content><citefragment searchtype="CASE-NAME-REF"><emph typestyle="it">Attorney-General (NSW) v Mundey</emph></citefragment><citefragment searchtype="CASE-CITE-REF"> <ci:span spanid="cr000051-001">[1972] 2 NSWLR 887</ci:span></citefragment> <remotelink dpsi="0018" refpt="655" remotekey1="REFPTID" service="DOC-ID"><inlineobject alttext="Click for CaseBase entry" attachment="web-server" filename="cbcc.gif" type="image"/></remotelink></ci:content></ci:cite>), I am by no means satisfied that it is proper to describe proceedings such as the present as criminal in nature (see, eg <ci:cite searchtype="CASE-REF"><ci:case><ci:caseinfo><ci:decisiondate year="1965"/></ci:caseinfo><ci:caseref ID="cr000052" spanref="cr000052-001" status="unval"><ci:reporter value="CLR"/><ci:volume num="112"/><ci:page num="483"/></ci:caseref><ci:caseref ID="cr000053" spanref="cr000053-002" status="unval"><ci:reporter value="ALR"/><ci:edition><ci:date year="1966"/></ci:edition><ci:page num="387"/></ci:caseref><ci:caseref ID="cr000054" spanref="cr000054-003"><ci:reporter value="urj"/><ci:refnum num="BC6500220"/></ci:caseref></ci:case><ci:content><citefragment searchtype="CASE-NAME-REF"><emph typestyle="it">Australian Consolidated Press Ltd v Morgan</emph></citefragment><citefragment searchtype="CASE-CITE-REF"> <ci:span spanid="cr000052-001" status="unval">(1965) 112 CLR 483</ci:span>; <ci:span spanid="cr000053-002" status="unval">[1966] ALR 387</ci:span>; <ci:span spanid="cr000054-003"> BC6500220</ci:span></citefragment> <remotelink dpsi="0018" refpt="3674" remotekey1="REFPTID" service="DOC-ID"><inlineobject alttext="Click for CaseBase entry" attachment="web-server" filename="cbcc.gif" type="image"/></remotelink></ci:content></ci:cite> where a distinction is drawn between criminal contempt and contempt in procedure). Nonetheless, since the potential consequences to a person such as the plaintiff are attachment or, perhaps, a fine, it is, I think proper to require such a standard of proof in such case and that, accordingly, is the standard which I have applied in the present case (see also, <ci:cite searchtype="CASE-REF"><ci:case><ci:caseinfo><ci:decisiondate year="1976"/></ci:caseinfo><ci:caseref ID="cr000055" spanref="cr000055-001"><ci:reporter value="ALR"/><ci:volume num="11"/><ci:page num="679"/></ci:caseref><ci:caseref ID="cr000056" spanref="cr000056-002" status="unval"><ci:reporter value="FLR"/><ci:volume num="25"/><ci:page num="475"/></ci:caseref></ci:case><ci:content><citefragment searchtype="CASE-NAME-REF"><emph typestyle="it">Marriage of Sahari</emph></citefragment><citefragment searchtype="CASE-CITE-REF"> <ci:span spanid="cr000055-001">(1976) 11 ALR 679</ci:span>; <ci:span spanid="cr000056-002" status="unval">25 FLR 475</ci:span></citefragment> <remotelink dpsi="0018" refpt="43805" remotekey1="REFPTID" service="DOC-ID"><inlineobject alttext="Click for CaseBase entry" attachment="web-server" filename="cbcc.gif" type="image"/></remotelink></ci:content></ci:cite> and cases there cited).</text></p>
<p>
<text>In the long run, however, what is involved is principally an evaluation of the credibility on the one hand of the defendant, who asserts, and of the plaintiff, who denies, the alleged incidents, for with the exception of the alleged incidents of 14 December 1977, and of 8 August 1978, no person other than the defendant's children was present on any alleged occasion. Having made such an evaluation I am satisfied that I should accept the defendant's evidence and reject that proffered by the plaintiff.</text></p></case:judgmentbody></case:judgment>
</case:judgments>
</case:content>
</case:body></CASEDOC>