<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!DOCTYPE CASEDOC PUBLIC "-//LEXISNEXIS//DTD GLP Casedoc v005//EN" "casedoc-norm.dtd">
<CASEDOC type="fulltext" xmlns:case="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/case" xmlns:ci="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/ci" xmlns:comm="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/comm" xmlns:cttr="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/cttr" xmlns:dict="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/dict" xmlns:dig="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/dig" xmlns:docinfo="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/docinfo" xmlns:frm="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/frm" xmlns:glp="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp" xmlns:in="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/in" xmlns:jrnl="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/jrnl" xmlns:leg="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/leg" xmlns:lnci="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnci" xmlns:lncle="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lncle" xmlns:lnclx="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnclx" xmlns:lndel="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lndel" xmlns:lndocmeta="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lndocmeta" xmlns:lngntxt="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lngntxt" xmlns:lnlit="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnlit" xmlns:lnv="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnv" xmlns:lnvni="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnvni" xmlns:lnvx="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnvx" xmlns:lnvxe="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnvxe" xmlns:nitf="urn:nitf:iptc.org.20010418.NITF" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3c.org/1999/xhtml">
<docinfo partitionnum="3"><docinfo:dpsi id-string="05CC"/><docinfo:doc-heading>[456,165] PARTNERSHIP PACIFIC LTD v KILLEN</docinfo:doc-heading><docinfo:doc-id>UCPN_PRACDEC.SGM_UCPN.PRACDEC.456165</docinfo:doc-id><docinfo:doc-lang lang="en"/><docinfo:doc-country iso-cc="AU"/><docinfo:hier><docinfo:hierlev role="ancestor"><heading><title>PRACTICE DECISIONS</title></heading><docinfo:hierlev role="ancestor"><heading><title>PRACTICE DECISIONS</title></heading><docinfo:hierlev role="me"><heading><edpnum>[456,165]</edpnum><title>PARTNERSHIP PACIFIC LTD v KILLEN</title></heading></docinfo:hierlev></docinfo:hierlev></docinfo:hierlev></docinfo:hier><docinfo:bookseqnum>160110000</docinfo:bookseqnum><docinfo:lbu-meta><docinfo:metaitem name="lbu-sourcename" value="Ritchie's Uniform Civil Procedure NSW"/><docinfo:metaitem name="parent-docid" value="UCPN.PRACDEC"/><docinfo:metaitem name="parent-filename" value="pracdec.xml"/><docinfo:metaitem name="parent-docid" value="UCPN_PRACDEC.SGM_UCPN.PRACDEC.456165"/><docinfo:metaitem name="parent-filename" value="pracdec1022.xml"/></docinfo:lbu-meta><docinfo:selector>case</docinfo:selector><docinfo:load-date><date day="11" month="09" year="2012">11 September 2012</date></docinfo:load-date></docinfo>
<case:body><heading searchtype="PRACTICE-NOTE"><edpnum><refpt id="UCPN.PRACDEC.456165" type="ext"/>[456,165]</edpnum></heading>
<case:headnote>
<case:info><case:casename searchtype="PRACTICE-NOTE">PARTNERSHIP PACIFIC LTD v KILLEN</case:casename></case:info>
<case:info>
<case:courtinfo><case:courtname>Supreme Court NSW, Court of Appeal</case:courtname>
<case:judges><case:judge>Moffitt P, Reynolds and Hutley JJA</case:judge>
</case:judges><case:dates><case:decisiondate>10 April 1979</case:decisiondate></case:dates>
<case:filenum>CA No 112/79</case:filenum>
</case:courtinfo></case:info><catchwordgrp><catchwords><catchphrase>Expedited hearing application</catchphrase></catchwords>
</catchwordgrp></case:headnote><case:content>
<case:judgments><case:judgment><case:courtinfo><case:judges><case:judge>Moffitt P</case:judge></case:judges></case:courtinfo>
<case:judgmentbody>
<p>
<text>This is an <emph typestyle="it">ex parte</emph> application for expedition of an appeal filed today in respect of a decision given by Needham J in proceedings about to commence before him. The appellant is not a party to those proceedings but is a witness served with a subpoena to produce documents. It made an application to Needham J to have the subpoena set aside on the basis that it was oppressive. His Honour dismissed the application. He is about to commence the proceedings which are expected to be very lengthy. He has delayed insisting on the production of the documents for several days.</text></p>
<p>
<text>We do not pause to consider whether or not leave is required but have called on counsel to debate with us the grounds on which it is proposed to argue any appeal. Thus we have considered the subject matter of the appeal sufficiently to appreciate the strength of the proposed appeal. Although we are not called upon at this point to finally determine the questions sought to be raised, we consider it appropriate to say that having heard counsel's arguments we are of the view that the appeal completely lacks merit.</text></p>
<p>
<text>We observe further that there is no claim for privilege and that there was no evidence at first instance or before this court that to answer the subpoena would involve difficulty for the applicant or would be oppressive in fact.</text></p>
<p>
<text>There is no stay of proceedings and there has been no application for any stay of proceedings, and if there had been this court would have refused it. Although the learned judge deferred acting upon the subpoena for a day or two, we would say, with respect, that there does not appear to be any reason why he should now not proceed to act on the ruling he has given in the ordinary course of proceedings before him.</text></p>
<p>
<text>We express some concern at proceedings being interrupted or sought to be interrupted by the kind of procedures sought to be invoked in this court in this instance. Regrettably some changed methods sought to be adopted by some counsel in the conduct of trials or proceedings at first instance, all too frequently both in respect of committal proceedings to which we recently referred, and now apparently extending into civil trials, are such that intermediate decisions at first instance are sought to be litigated on appeal and the proceedings at first instance delayed while these distracting diversions are indulged in. The present application falls into this class.</text></p>
<p>
<text>Accordingly the court dismisses the application for an expedited hearing. We are not called upon, of course, to determine the appeal and we do not determine it now, but if the applicant seeks to proceed with it, the appeal can take its normal course and come up for hearing in the ordinary way.</text></p></case:judgmentbody></case:judgment>
</case:judgments>
</case:content>
</case:body></CASEDOC>