<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!DOCTYPE CASEDOC PUBLIC "-//LEXISNEXIS//DTD GLP Casedoc v005//EN" "casedoc-norm.dtd">
<CASEDOC type="fulltext" xmlns:case="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/case" xmlns:ci="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/ci" xmlns:comm="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/comm" xmlns:cttr="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/cttr" xmlns:dict="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/dict" xmlns:dig="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/dig" xmlns:docinfo="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/docinfo" xmlns:frm="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/frm" xmlns:glp="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp" xmlns:in="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/in" xmlns:jrnl="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/jrnl" xmlns:leg="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/leg" xmlns:lnci="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnci" xmlns:lncle="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lncle" xmlns:lnclx="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnclx" xmlns:lndel="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lndel" xmlns:lndocmeta="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lndocmeta" xmlns:lngntxt="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lngntxt" xmlns:lnlit="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnlit" xmlns:lnv="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnv" xmlns:lnvni="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnvni" xmlns:lnvx="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnvx" xmlns:lnvxe="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnvxe" xmlns:nitf="urn:nitf:iptc.org.20010418.NITF" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3c.org/1999/xhtml">
<docinfo partitionnum="3"><docinfo:dpsi id-string="05CC"/><docinfo:doc-heading>[456,150] KIRBY v SOUTHERN PACIFIC HOTEL CORPORATION LTD</docinfo:doc-heading><docinfo:doc-id>UCPN_PRACDEC.SGM_UCPN.PRACDEC.456150</docinfo:doc-id><docinfo:doc-lang lang="en"/><docinfo:doc-country iso-cc="AU"/><docinfo:hier><docinfo:hierlev role="ancestor"><heading><title>PRACTICE DECISIONS</title></heading><docinfo:hierlev role="ancestor"><heading><title>PRACTICE DECISIONS</title></heading><docinfo:hierlev role="me"><heading><edpnum>[456,150]</edpnum><title>KIRBY v SOUTHERN PACIFIC HOTEL CORPORATION LTD</title></heading></docinfo:hierlev></docinfo:hierlev></docinfo:hierlev></docinfo:hier><docinfo:bookseqnum>160090000</docinfo:bookseqnum><docinfo:lbu-meta><docinfo:metaitem name="lbu-sourcename" value="Ritchie's Uniform Civil Procedure NSW"/><docinfo:metaitem name="parent-docid" value="UCPN.PRACDEC"/><docinfo:metaitem name="parent-filename" value="pracdec.xml"/><docinfo:metaitem name="parent-docid" value="UCPN_PRACDEC.SGM_UCPN.PRACDEC.456150"/><docinfo:metaitem name="parent-filename" value="pracdec1018.xml"/></docinfo:lbu-meta><docinfo:selector>case</docinfo:selector><docinfo:load-date><date day="11" month="09" year="2012">11 September 2012</date></docinfo:load-date></docinfo>
<case:body><heading searchtype="PRACTICE-NOTE"><edpnum><refpt id="UCPN.PRACDEC.456150" type="ext"/>[456,150]</edpnum></heading>
<case:headnote>
<case:info><case:casename searchtype="PRACTICE-NOTE">KIRBY v SOUTHERN PACIFIC HOTEL CORPORATION LTD</case:casename></case:info>
<case:info>
<case:courtinfo><case:courtname>Supreme Court NSW</case:courtname>
<case:judges><case:judge>Master Allen</case:judge>
</case:judges><case:dates><case:decisiondate>5 May 1983</case:decisiondate></case:dates>
<case:filenum>CL No 11419/82</case:filenum>
</case:courtinfo></case:info><catchwordgrp><catchwords><catchphrase>UCPR r 21 &#x2014; [SCR Pt 23 r 6]</catchphrase><catchphrase>Discovery</catchphrase><catchphrase>Documents obtainable by a party under Freedom of Information Act 1982 (Cth)</catchphrase></catchwords>
</catchwordgrp></case:headnote><case:content>
<case:judgments><case:judgment><case:courtinfo><case:judges><case:judge>Master Allen</case:judge></case:judges></case:courtinfo>
<case:judgmentbody>
<p>
<text>The substantial point with which I am now concerned is whether the plaintiff should be ordered to make discovery of a copy of his income tax returns for the financial years 1978, 1979, 1980 and 1981. The unfortunate position appears to exist that the copies which the plaintiff originally had have been mislaid. The circumstances of that mislaying are for the moment irrelevant.</text></p>
<p>
<text>There is no doubt that copies of the income tax returns of the plaintiff would be relevant documents in this litigation. They directly touch upon issues which are central.</text></p>
<p>
<text>On behalf of the defendant, who seeks the order for discovery, it is put that the plaintiff has a legal right to obtain a copy of these returns from the Commissioner for Taxation. That proposition, startling on the face of it, appears now to be supported by the Freedom of Information Act 1982 (Cth).</text></p>
<p>
<text>Several objections are taken on behalf of the plaintiff. The first is that the documents, discovery whereof is sought, are not documents presently in existence but documents which would be brought into existence by the Commissioner for Taxation pursuant to his statutory obligation to make copies of the documents which he has.</text></p>
<p>
<text>The plaintiff, it is said, does not himself have control over the original returns themselves. Discovery does not extend to documents which are not in existence but which are needed to be brought into existence if discovery is to be practicable.</text></p>
<p>
<text>The second objection is that if the legal right does exist in the plaintiff to procure a copy of his tax returns the plaintiff would have to pay a charge therefor and in the light of that requirement he does not have a legal right presently existing to procure them.</text></p>
<p>
<text>The third objection is that the legal right does not exist because there are statutory grounds under which the authority can refuse the request to make available a copy of the document.</text></p>
<p>
<text>In my opinion none of these objections is well founded.</text></p>
<p>
<text>The first objection is that the document, discovery of which is sought, does not exist. It would exist only if it is brought into existence by being made as a copy of some other document. In <ci:cite searchtype="CASE-REF"><ci:case><ci:caseref ID="cr000080" spanref="cr000080-001" status="unval"><ci:reporter value="WLR"/><ci:volume num="1"/><ci:edition><ci:date year="1980"/></ci:edition><ci:page num="627"/></ci:caseref><ci:caseref anaphref="cr000080" spanref="cr000080-002" status="unval"><ci:pinpoint num="635" targettype="page"/></ci:caseref></ci:case><ci:content><citefragment searchtype="CASE-NAME-REF"><emph typestyle="it">Lonrho Ltd v Shell Petroleum Co Ltd</emph></citefragment><citefragment searchtype="CASE-CITE-REF"> <ci:span spanid="cr000080-001" status="unval">[1980] 1 WLR 627</ci:span> <ci:span spanid="cr000080-002" status="unval">at 635</ci:span></citefragment> <remotelink dpsi="0018" refpt="5122" remotekey1="REFPTID" service="DOC-ID"><inlineobject alttext="Click for CaseBase entry" attachment="web-server" filename="cbcc.gif" type="image"/></remotelink></ci:content></ci:cite>, Lord Diplock stated the accepted test. It is that the person against whom the order is sought has &#x201c;a presently enforceable legal right to obtain from who actually holds the document, inspection of it without the need to obtain the consent of anyone else&#x201d;. That statement does not in direct language cover the present situation.</text></p>
<p>
<text>Counsel cannot put to me any authority for what is a novel proposition, that discovery extends to a copy where the person against whom the order is sought has the right to obtain that copy of a document which presently is not in existence, and it has that right without the need of obtaining the consent of anyone else. But the law of discovery is not frozen; the powers of the court have not become effete and when unlikely situations arise the court can meet those situations within the spirit and principle of what hitherto has been established.</text></p>
<p>
<text>I have no hesitation in saying that the power of the court does extend to ordering discovery of a copy of a document where the person against whom the order is sought has a presently enforceable legal right to obtain that copy without the consent of anyone else.</text></p>
<p>
<text>As to the second point that a charge might be levied by the Commission, there is no evidence that such a charge would be levied but if it were I still would not consider that that was an obstacle to the court ordering discovery. The right exists. The fact that an incident of the exercise of that right might be the paying of a charge does not destroy the existence of the present right.</text></p>
<p>
<text>It is trite law that if one has an agent who has one's documents and one has a legal right to demand from him that he send the documents across one must make discovery. One is not excused because under the terms of the contract of agency one may have to pay one's own agent a fee for the clerical work and administrative services involved.</text></p>
<p>
<text>The third point is that the Commissioner, or rather the Minister to be more precise, might have a discretion to decline to make a copy. The grounds on which the discretion could be exercised are set out in s 24(1)(b). The possibility of any of those grounds being applicable in the present case is so remote that I consider there is no substance whatever in that objection.</text></p>
<p>
<text>However, despite the views which I have expressed I do not make a formal order for discovery. The spirit of what the court wishes to achieve in the exercise of the discretion, which in my view is undoubted, is best obtained by my giving the following direction.</text></p>
<p>
<text>I direct that within seven days the plaintiff do make application to the Commissioner for Taxation for the provision to him pursuant to the provisions of the Freedom of Information Act 1982  of a copy of each of his income tax returns for the financial years which ended respectively on 30 June 1978, 30 June 1979, 30 June 1980 and 30 June 1981.</text></p>
<p>
<text>I do further direct that the plaintiff pay any fee or charge required by the Commissioner for the provision of such copies upon being paid by the defendant an amount equivalent thereto.</text></p>
<p>
<text>I do further direct that within seven days after receiving from the Commissioner a copy of the said returns or any of them the plaintiff do furnish to the defendant a further copy of each such document at the reasonable cost of the defendant.</text></p>
<p>
<text>[Master Allen then dealt with matters not germane to this report.]</text></p></case:judgmentbody></case:judgment>
</case:judgments>
</case:content>
</case:body></CASEDOC>