<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!DOCTYPE CASEDOC PUBLIC "-//LEXISNEXIS//DTD GLP Casedoc v005//EN" "casedoc-norm.dtd">
<CASEDOC type="fulltext" xmlns:case="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/case" xmlns:ci="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/ci" xmlns:comm="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/comm" xmlns:cttr="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/cttr" xmlns:dict="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/dict" xmlns:dig="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/dig" xmlns:docinfo="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/docinfo" xmlns:frm="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/frm" xmlns:glp="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp" xmlns:in="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/in" xmlns:jrnl="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/jrnl" xmlns:leg="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/glp/leg" xmlns:lnci="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnci" xmlns:lncle="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lncle" xmlns:lnclx="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnclx" xmlns:lndel="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lndel" xmlns:lndocmeta="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lndocmeta" xmlns:lngntxt="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lngntxt" xmlns:lnlit="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnlit" xmlns:lnv="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnv" xmlns:lnvni="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnvni" xmlns:lnvx="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnvx" xmlns:lnvxe="http://www.lexis-nexis.com/lnvxe" xmlns:nitf="urn:nitf:iptc.org.20010418.NITF" xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3c.org/1999/xhtml">
<docinfo partitionnum="3"><docinfo:dpsi id-string="05CC"/><docinfo:doc-heading>[456,105] BRAND v PALLISAR PTY LTD; STRATA PLAN NO 2240 THIRD PARTY</docinfo:doc-heading><docinfo:doc-id>UCPN_PRACDEC.SGM_UCPN.PRACDEC.456105</docinfo:doc-id><docinfo:doc-lang lang="en"/><docinfo:doc-country iso-cc="AU"/><docinfo:hier><docinfo:hierlev role="ancestor"><heading><title>PRACTICE DECISIONS</title></heading><docinfo:hierlev role="ancestor"><heading><title>PRACTICE DECISIONS</title></heading><docinfo:hierlev role="me"><heading><edpnum>[456,105]</edpnum><title>BRAND v PALLISAR PTY LTD; STRATA PLAN NO 2240 THIRD PARTY</title></heading></docinfo:hierlev></docinfo:hierlev></docinfo:hierlev></docinfo:hier><docinfo:bookseqnum>160010000</docinfo:bookseqnum><docinfo:lbu-meta><docinfo:metaitem name="lbu-sourcename" value="Ritchie's Uniform Civil Procedure NSW"/><docinfo:metaitem name="parent-docid" value="UCPN.PRACDEC"/><docinfo:metaitem name="parent-filename" value="pracdec.xml"/><docinfo:metaitem name="parent-docid" value="UCPN_PRACDEC.SGM_UCPN.PRACDEC.456105"/><docinfo:metaitem name="parent-filename" value="pracdec1002.xml"/></docinfo:lbu-meta><docinfo:selector>case</docinfo:selector><docinfo:load-date><date day="11" month="09" year="2012">11 September 2012</date></docinfo:load-date></docinfo>
<case:body><heading searchtype="PRACTICE-NOTE"><edpnum><refpt id="UCPN.PRACDEC.456105" type="ext"/>[456,105]</edpnum></heading>
<case:headnote>
<case:info><case:casename searchtype="PRACTICE-NOTE">BRAND v PALLISAR PTY LTD; STRATA PLAN NO 2240 THIRD PARTY</case:casename></case:info>
<case:info>
<case:courtinfo><case:courtname>Local Court of New South Wales, Sydney</case:courtname>
<case:judges><case:judge>Elms M</case:judge>
</case:judges><case:dates><case:decisiondate>20 April 1990</case:decisiondate></case:dates>
<case:filenum>No 8293/88</case:filenum>
</case:courtinfo></case:info><catchwordgrp><catchwords><catchphrase>Jurisdiction</catchphrase><catchphrase>Claim for damages in the nature of mesne profits</catchphrase><catchphrase>Local Courts (Civil Claims) Act 1970 s 12</catchphrase><catchphrase>Local Court has no jurisdiction to apply equitable remedies or principles.</catchphrase></catchwords>
</catchwordgrp></case:headnote><case:content>
<glp:note>
<p>
<text>[The plaintiff sued the defendant claiming damages under s 66M  of the Conveyancing Act 1919. The plaintiff had purchased a home unit, and after contracts were exchanged, she alleged that the property had been damaged before the risk passed to her. These issues were ultimately resolved in favour of the plaintiff. During the hearing it became evident that the plaintiff had entered into occupation of the premises prior to completion, and the defendant obtained leave to file a cross-claim claiming damages in the nature of mesne profits or alternatively damages for breach of contract. After reviewing the evidence surrounding the plaintiff's claim, his Worship went on:]</text></p></glp:note>
<case:judgments><case:judgment><case:courtinfo><case:judges><case:judge>Elms M</case:judge></case:judges></case:courtinfo>
<case:judgmentbody>
<p>
<text>I turn now to the aspect of the case surrounding the plaintiff's unilateral occupation of the subject premises, a fact which only emerged during her cross-examination. In this regard, the defendant called two witnesses. Mr Eric Jury, a director of the vendor company, gave evidence that there was no agreement between the parties that the plaintiff was entitled to enter into occupation from 21 January, 1988 until the date of settlement. Mr Nassim Farah, who was well acquainted with the unit, the subject of these proceedings, gave evidence that a reasonable rental for same, being a two bedroom unit, was $350 per week. On this basis, the defendant (cross-claimant) has based its claim against the plaintiff (cross-defendant), upon a claim for <emph typestyle="it">mesne</emph> profits from the date the plaintiff entered into possession, 21 January, 1988, until the date of completion (11 February, 1988). In the alternative, the plaintiff claims damages for breach of contract.</text></p>
<p>
<text>In the defendant's notice of cross-claim, para 5 asserted that it was an express term of the contract that the cross-defendant would pay in the event that the cross-claimant agreed to permit occupation, a licence fee. As I have previously said, Mr Dupree conceded that this was a misreading of cl 18 of the contract. The agreement between the parties dated 1 December, 1987 provides on the first page (para K) that the benefit of possession is to be given as at the date of:</text></p>
<p>
<l>
<li>
<lilabel>&#x2022;</lilabel>
<p><text>completion</text></p></li>
<li>
<lilabel>&#x2022;</lilabel>
<p><text>with vacant possession</text></p></li>
<li>
<lilabel>&#x2022;</lilabel>
<p><text>subject to existing tenancies or occupancies under the vendor as particularised in the third schedule.</text></p>
<p>
<text>No existing tenancies or occupancies are particularised in the third schedule, and therefore on a proper reading of the contract the parties have agreed that the benefit of possession is to be given to the purchaser with vacant possession as at the date of completion. In this regard, cl 17 of the contract provides that &#x201c;the property is sold with the benefit of possession to be given to the purchaser at the time and in the manner stipulated in K of the particulars or elsewhere in the particulars of agreement&#x201d;. Clause 18 foreshadows circumstances where the purchaser is given the benefit of possession before transfer of title and imposes certain obligations on the purchaser in this regard. However, the very words &#x201c;if before transfer of title the purchaser <emph typestyle="it">is given</emph> the benefit of possession&#x201d; presupposes a further agreement between the parties. They do not presuppose a unilateral taking of possession by one party from the other in contravention of the very terms of the agreement itself.</text></p>
<p>
<text>The plaintiff (cross-defendant) has submitted through her counsel that this court has no jurisdiction to entertain a claim for damages arising from the use and occupation of premises where one party to a contract has taken possession of the matter contracted to be sold prior to the appointed date of completion or possession; and has cited <ci:cite searchtype="CASE-REF"><ci:case><ci:caseref ID="cr000001" spanref="cr000001-001"><ci:reporter value="urj"/><ci:refnum num="BC9002731"/></ci:caseref></ci:case><ci:content><citefragment searchtype="CASE-NAME-REF"><emph typestyle="it">Miaoli Holdings Pty Ltd v Somerville</emph></citefragment><citefragment searchtype="CASE-CITE-REF"> <ci:span spanid="cr000001-001"> (NSWSC, Cohen J, No 2194/87, 14 February 1990, unreported, BC9002731</ci:span></citefragment></ci:content></ci:cite>). On the authority of that decision, Mr Minehan has submitted that only the Equity Court has jurisdiction. However, I do not understand that decision to be authority for the proposition stated, and in particular, I do not understand that decision to oust a claim for <emph typestyle="it">mesne</emph> profits or, by analogy, damages for breach of contract where a purchaser unilaterally enters into possession prior to the appointed date of completion. Indeed, a distinction was sought to be drawn between an occupation fee, and a claim for interest arising out of occupation, by counsel for the cross-defendants in that case. Without deciding that point, Cohen J, allowed the matter to proceed &#x201c;on the basis that the defendant could make a claim for an occupation fee based upon the interest which it is said would be payable&#x201d; (see p 2 of the judgment).</text></p>
<p>
<text>As I understand the jurisdiction point, s 12(1) of the Local Courts (Civil Claims) Act, 1970, so far as is here relevant, gives the Local Court jurisdiction to &#x201c;hear and determine actions for the recovery of any debt, demand or damage, whether liquidated or unliquidated &#x2026; in which the amount claimed is not more than $10,000 &#x2026;&#x201d; A claim for <emph typestyle="it">mesne</emph> profits is certainly a claim for the recovery of any debt, demand or damage within the meaning of those words as used in the section. Many of the cases associated with <emph typestyle="it">mesne</emph> profits deal with tenancy situations where, for example, a lessee has vacated leaving others in possession. However, I do not see the action as confined to those situations, and indeed, the cases cited in <emph typestyle="it">McGregor on Damages</emph>, 14th ed, Sweet &amp; Maxwell, 1980, at para 1136 and following would seem to suggest otherwise.</text></p>
<p>
<text>Salmond on the <emph typestyle="it">Law of Torts</emph>, 17th ed, Sweet &amp; Maxwell, 1981, states at p 561:</text></p>
<p>
<text>&#x201c; <emph typestyle="it">any person</emph> [my emphasis] wrongfully disposed of land has, in addition to a right of action for the recovery of the land, a right of action for damages in respect of all loss suffered by him during the period of his dispossession. Such an action is termed an action for <emph typestyle="it">mesne</emph> profits &#x2026; Whether the dispossession had or had not been affected by way of trespass, the claim for <emph typestyle="it">mesne</emph>  profits was always in form a claim for damages for a continuing trespass upon the land &#x2026; The law, then, seems to be as follows: a person dispossessed of land may:</text></p>
<p>
<text>(1) sue for recovery and for <emph typestyle="it">mesne</emph> profits in one action;</text></p>
<p>
<text>(2) sue for <emph typestyle="it">mesne</emph> profits, if he has already got back into possession;</text></p>
<p>
<text>(3) sue for <emph typestyle="it">mesne</emph> profits without recovery of possession, if his interest in the land has already come to an end.&#x201d;</text></p>
<p>
<text>If a stranger had assumed possession of the defendant's property in the same circumstances as did the plaintiff in this case, it seems to me to be unarguable that the defendant would have been entitled to bring an action for <emph typestyle="it">mesne</emph> profits, and I cannot logically see why the situation should be any different simply because there happens to be a contract between the parties, an essential term of which the plaintiff has breached by a trespassery taking of possession prior to the date appointed for same in the contract.</text></p>
<p>
<text>The claim for <emph typestyle="it">mesne</emph> profits is a claim for damages at common law. Equity imposes a gloss upon the common law to the effect that interest should be paid on the unpaid purchase price in circumstances where a purchaser is let into possession of property in circumstances where there is no agreement that interest is not to be paid. This is the rule in <ci:cite searchtype="CASE-REF"><ci:case><ci:caseinfo><ci:decisiondate year="1852"/></ci:caseinfo><ci:caseref ID="cr000002" spanref="cr000002-001" status="unval"><ci:reporter value="HLCas"/><ci:volume num="3"/><ci:page num="565"/></ci:caseref><ci:caseref ID="cr000003" spanref="cr000003-002" status="unval"><ci:reporter value="ER"/><ci:volume num="10"/><ci:page num="222"/></ci:caseref></ci:case><ci:content><citefragment searchtype="CASE-NAME-REF"><emph typestyle="it">Birch v Joy</emph></citefragment><citefragment searchtype="CASE-CITE-REF"> <ci:span spanid="cr000002-001" status="unval">(1852) 3 HL Cas 565</ci:span>; <ci:span spanid="cr000003-002" status="unval">10 ER 222</ci:span></citefragment> <remotelink dpsi="0018" refpt="26959" remotekey1="REFPTID" service="DOC-ID"><inlineobject alttext="Click for CaseBase entry" attachment="web-server" filename="cbcc.gif" type="image"/></remotelink></ci:content></ci:cite>, cited by Cohen J in the <emph typestyle="it">Miaoli Holdings</emph>
<fnr fnrtoken="SMN.PRACDEC.190110.FTN1-R" fntoken="SMN.PRACDEC.190110.FTN1">1</fnr> case, above, <ci:cite searchtype="CASE-REF"><ci:case><ci:caseref ID="cr000005" spanref="cr000005-000"><ci:reporter value="urj"/><ci:pinpoint num="15" targettype="para"/></ci:caseref></ci:case><ci:content><citefragment searchtype="CASE-CITE-REF"><ci:span spanid="cr000005-000">at 15</ci:span></citefragment></ci:content></ci:cite>.</text></p>
<p>
<text>Now it is, I think, evident that a Local Court would have no jurisdiction to apply an equitable remedy or principle such as the rule in <emph typestyle="it">Birch v Joy</emph>,
<fnr fnrtoken="SMN.PRACDEC.190110.FTN2-R" fntoken="SMN.PRACDEC.190110.FTN2">2</fnr> above. However, a Local Court does have jurisdiction pursuant to s 12(1) of the Local Courts (Civil Claims) Act to award damages. In circumstances where the award of damages would be tantamount to a decree of specific performance, again the Local Court has no jurisdiction: see for example, <ci:cite searchtype="CASE-REF"><ci:case><ci:caseref ID="cr000008" spanref="cr000008-001" status="unval"><ci:reporter value="QB"/><ci:volume num="2"/><ci:edition><ci:date year="1892"/></ci:edition><ci:page num="255"/></ci:caseref></ci:case><ci:content><citefragment searchtype="CASE-NAME-REF"><emph typestyle="it">Foster v Reeves</emph></citefragment><citefragment searchtype="CASE-CITE-REF"> <ci:span spanid="cr000008-001" status="unval">[1892] 2 QB 255</ci:span></citefragment> <remotelink dpsi="0018" refpt="4390" remotekey1="REFPTID" service="DOC-ID"><inlineobject alttext="Click for CaseBase entry" attachment="web-server" filename="cbcc.gif" type="image"/></remotelink></ci:content></ci:cite> and <ci:cite searchtype="CASE-REF"><ci:case><ci:caseref ID="cr000009" spanref="cr000009-001" status="unval"><ci:reporter value="SASR"/><ci:edition><ci:date year="1929"/></ci:edition><ci:page num="274"/></ci:caseref></ci:case><ci:content><citefragment searchtype="CASE-NAME-REF"><emph typestyle="it">Moore v Dimond</emph></citefragment><citefragment searchtype="CASE-CITE-REF"> <ci:span spanid="cr000009-001" status="unval">[1929] SASR 274</ci:span></citefragment> <remotelink dpsi="0018" refpt="116739" remotekey1="REFPTID" service="DOC-ID"><inlineobject alttext="Click for CaseBase entry" attachment="web-server" filename="cbcc.gif" type="image"/></remotelink></ci:content></ci:cite>. However, this is not such a situation. In this instance, the defendant (cross-claimant) is suing simply to recovery damages by way of <emph typestyle="it">mesne</emph> profits for the trespassory occupation of his property, and I seems to me that in this regard, it is entitled to succeed. It should be evidence from what I have said that I am therefore not administering equitable remedies in contravention of the principles enunciated in <ci:cite searchtype="CASE-REF"><ci:case><ci:caseinfo><ci:decisiondate year="1975"/></ci:caseinfo><ci:caseref ID="cr000010" spanref="cr000010-001" status="unval"><ci:reporter value="BPR"/><ci:volume num="1"/><ci:page num="9642"/></ci:caseref></ci:case><ci:content><citefragment searchtype="CASE-NAME-REF"><emph typestyle="it">Joblin v Carney</emph></citefragment><citefragment searchtype="CASE-CITE-REF"> <ci:span spanid="cr000010-001" status="unval">(1975) 1 BPR 9642</ci:span></citefragment> <remotelink dpsi="0018" refpt="213431" remotekey1="REFPTID" service="DOC-ID"><inlineobject alttext="Click for CaseBase entry" attachment="web-server" filename="cbcc.gif" type="image"/></remotelink></ci:content></ci:cite> and Meagher, Gummow and Lehane, <emph typestyle="it">Equity: Doctrines and Remedies</emph>, 2nd ed, Butterworths 1984 at [249]. There is an old South Australian authority, <ci:cite searchtype="CASE-REF"><ci:case><ci:caseinfo><ci:decisiondate year="1909"/></ci:caseinfo><ci:caseref ID="cr000011" spanref="cr000011-001" status="unval"><ci:reporter value="SALR"/><ci:page num="28"/></ci:caseref></ci:case><ci:content><citefragment searchtype="CASE-NAME-REF"><emph typestyle="it">Douglas v Hill</emph></citefragment><citefragment searchtype="CASE-CITE-REF"> <ci:span spanid="cr000011-001" status="unval">(1909) SALR 28</ci:span></citefragment></ci:content></ci:cite>, to the effect that s 33 of the Local Courts Act, 1886 (which is to all intents and purposes identical with s 5 of the Law Reform (Law and Equity) Act, 1972 in this state) gives the Local Court power to apply equitable doctrines and to give equitable damages. However, that decision has limited applicability in this state having regard to the principles enunciated in <ci:cite searchtype="CASE-REF"><ci:case><ci:caseinfo><ci:decisiondate year="1975"/></ci:caseinfo><ci:caseref ID="cr000012" spanref="cr000012-001" status="unval"><ci:reporter value="BPR"/><ci:volume num="1"/><ci:page num="9642"/></ci:caseref></ci:case><ci:content><citefragment searchtype="CASE-NAME-REF"><emph typestyle="it">Joblin v Carney</emph></citefragment><citefragment searchtype="CASE-CITE-REF"> <ci:span spanid="cr000012-001" status="unval">(1975) 1 BPR 9642</ci:span></citefragment> <remotelink dpsi="0018" refpt="213431" remotekey1="REFPTID" service="DOC-ID"><inlineobject alttext="Click for CaseBase entry" attachment="web-server" filename="cbcc.gif" type="image"/></remotelink></ci:content></ci:cite>, above.</text></p>
<p>
<text>As for the measure of damages in a claim for <emph typestyle="it">mesne</emph> profits, it is not necessary for the cross-claimant to prove loss, in the sense that it would have been able to relet the property in question during the period of wrongful occupation. As the English Court of Appeal said in <ci:cite searchtype="CASE-REF"><ci:case><ci:caseref ID="cr000013" spanref="cr000013-001" status="unval"><ci:reporter value="WLR"/><ci:volume num="1"/><ci:edition><ci:date year="1979"/></ci:edition><ci:page num="285"/></ci:caseref></ci:case><ci:content><citefragment searchtype="CASE-NAME-REF"><emph typestyle="it">Swordheath Properties Ltd v Tabet</emph></citefragment><citefragment searchtype="CASE-CITE-REF"> <ci:span spanid="cr000013-001" status="unval">[1979] 1 WLR 285</ci:span></citefragment> <remotelink dpsi="0018" refpt="105585" remotekey1="REFPTID" service="DOC-ID"><inlineobject alttext="Click for CaseBase entry" attachment="web-server" filename="cbcc.gif" type="image"/></remotelink></ci:content></ci:cite> (cited in <emph typestyle="it">McGregor on Damages</emph>, Sweet &amp; Maxwell, 1980, para 1137):</text></p>
<p>
<text>&#x201c;It appears to me (Megaw, LJ) to be clear, both as a matter of principle and of authority, that in a case of this sort, the plaintiff, when he has established that the defendant has remained on as a trespasser in residential property, is entitled, without bringing evidence that he could or would have let the property to someone else in the absence of the trespassing defendant, to have as damages for the trespass the value of the property as it would fairly be calculated; and in the absence of anything special in the particular case it would be the ordinary letting value of the property that would determine the amount of the damages.&#x201d;</text></p>
<p>
<text>In the present case, the plaintiff has agreed under cross-examination $300 per week was a fair and reasonable rent for the premises. She said that she had been told that the premises had been rented for $300 per week before it became vacant. Mr Farah gave evidence that somewhere between $325 and $350 per week was a reasonable letting fee for the subject premises at that time. In all the circumstances, and on the basis of Mr Farah's evidence, I propose to allow $325 per week as an appropriate amount which the claimant is entitled to have as damages on the basis of its claim for <emph typestyle="it">mesne</emph> profits. The relevant period from 21 January, 1988 to 11 February, 1988 is three weeks. The cross claimant is therefore entitled to succeed in its claim against the plaintiff (cross-defendant) in the sum of $975. It would also seem to me that the cross-claimant would have been entitled to success against the cross-defendant on the basis of the principles of unjust enrichment: she has obtained a benefit at the cross-claimant's expense, and it would be unjust to allow her to retain that benefit (see Goff and Jones, <emph typestyle="it">The Law of Restitution</emph>, 2nd ed, Sweet &amp; Maxwell, 1978, generally, but especially chapter I p 13 and following). The concept of benefit covers situations where an individual has been saved expense (<emph typestyle="it">ibid</emph>, p 14). However, since I was not addressed on the principles of unjust enrichment by either party, I do not propose to consider the matter in any detail.</text></p></li></l></p>
<pgrp>
<heading><title>Costs</title></heading>
<p>
<text>I have not yet had the benefit of submissions on the question of costs. However, it appears to me to be appropriate that I should give the parties some indication of the way in which I am thinking so that they can address me on the subject. I have already said that I take a dim view of the manner in which the action was commenced on behalf of the plaintiff. On the evidence before me, no attempt was made to see if some resolution of the matter could be achieved with the solicitor for the defendant by way of achieving a reduction in the purchase price after the plaintiff had quantified the amount to repaint the premises following the work carried out on the body corporate's behalf. A reduction in the purchase price is specifically contemplated by s 66M of the Conveyancing Act, 1919. Instead, the plaintiff simply went ahead and issued a plaint on 2 February 1988, while she was still in trespassory occupation of the premises. This may be seen as unduly fostering litigation and in my view is a matter to take into account when considering the discretionary matter of whether costs are to be awarded or not and if so in what amount.</text></p>
<p>
<text>The third party has succeeded against the defendant and it seems to me the third party should have its costs against the defendant regardless of what occurs between the plaintiff and the defendant on the question of costs. It is also my view that the cross-claimant should have its costs of the cross-claim having been successful in that regard.</text></p>
<p>
<text>I will hear further submissions on the question of costs. In the meantime, there will be a verdict for the plaintiff on the plaintiff's claim against the defendant in the sum of $940. There will be a verdict in the third party proceedings for the third party against the defendant. There will be a verdict for the cross-claimant (defendant) against the cross-defendant (plaintiff) in the sum of $975.</text></p></pgrp></case:judgmentbody></case:judgment>
<footnotegrp><footnote fnrtokens="SMN.PRACDEC.190110.FTN1-R" fntoken="SMN.PRACDEC.190110.FTN1" type="default"><fnlabel>1</fnlabel><fnbody>
<p><refpt id="SMN.PRACDEC.190110.FTN1" type="ext"/>
<text><ci:cite searchtype="CASE-REF"><ci:case><ci:caseref ID="cr000004" spanref="cr000004-001"><ci:reporter value="urj"/><ci:refnum num="BC9002731"/></ci:caseref></ci:case><ci:content><citefragment searchtype="CASE-NAME-REF"><emph typestyle="it">Miaoli Holdings Pty Ltd v Somerville</emph></citefragment><citefragment searchtype="CASE-CITE-REF"> <ci:span spanid="cr000004-001"> (NSWSC, Cohen J, No 2194/87, 14 February 1990, unreported, BC9002731</ci:span></citefragment></ci:content></ci:cite>)</text></p></fnbody></footnote>
<footnote fnrtokens="SMN.PRACDEC.190110.FTN2-R" fntoken="SMN.PRACDEC.190110.FTN2" type="default"><fnlabel>2</fnlabel><fnbody>
<p><refpt id="SMN.PRACDEC.190110.FTN2" type="ext"/>
<text><ci:cite searchtype="CASE-REF"><ci:case><ci:caseinfo><ci:decisiondate year="1852"/></ci:caseinfo><ci:caseref ID="cr000006" spanref="cr000006-001" status="unval"><ci:reporter value="HLCas"/><ci:volume num="3"/><ci:page num="565"/></ci:caseref><ci:caseref ID="cr000007" spanref="cr000007-002" status="unval"><ci:reporter value="ER"/><ci:volume num="10"/><ci:page num="222"/></ci:caseref></ci:case><ci:content><citefragment searchtype="CASE-NAME-REF"><emph typestyle="it">Birch v Joy</emph></citefragment><citefragment searchtype="CASE-CITE-REF"> <ci:span spanid="cr000006-001" status="unval">(1852) 3 HL Cas 565</ci:span>; <ci:span spanid="cr000007-002" status="unval">10 ER 222</ci:span></citefragment> <remotelink dpsi="0018" refpt="26959" remotekey1="REFPTID" service="DOC-ID"><inlineobject alttext="Click for CaseBase entry" attachment="web-server" filename="cbcc.gif" type="image"/></remotelink></ci:content></ci:cite></text></p></fnbody></footnote></footnotegrp>
</case:judgments>
</case:content>
</case:body></CASEDOC>